纳加登铜矿, 印度
2009年
嘿 嘿 当心 当心
Hey, hey. Watch out, watch out!
欢迎你 我的朋友!
Welcome my friend!
- 看到你真高兴 - 你能来我也很高兴
- Great to see you! - Glad you made it
那是阿吉特吧
This can't be Ajit.
他都长这么大了 真不敢相信
He's a little man already. Unbelievable.
艾德里安 你饿了吧?
I hope you're hungry, Adrian.
你好 阿帕娜 我饿坏了
I'm famished. How are you, Aparna?
我做了你爱吃的咖喱鱼
I made that fish curry you love.
我都等不及了
I can't wait.
她可是越来越漂亮了
She gets more beautiful every time I see her.
怎么回事?
Why is that?
很奇怪是吧?
Strange, isn't it?
可她做饭的手艺一直没见长
But her fish curry is still awful.
你在电话里神神秘秘的
You were mysterious on the phone.
为什么不去参加研讨会?
Why didn't you attend the conference?
你一会儿就知道了 艾德里安阁下
I will show you, Adrian, sir.
萨特南 别再叫我 "阁下"
Satnam, stop sir-ing me.
我们要下去多深?
How deep do we need to go?
3000多米
11000 feet.
我为此找遍了整个印度
Searched all over India for this dig.
这里曾是世界上最深的铜矿井
Used to be the deepest copper mine in the world.
还记得我弟弟格迪普吗? 他现在是一名学生
Remember my brother Gurdeep? He's a student now.
你好 赫尔姆斯利博士阁下
Namaste, Dr. Helmsley, sir.
艾德里安 叫我艾德里安就好
Adrian. It's just Adrian.
冰块就这么点 这哪够用
省着点用 好吗?
Just don't pour too much, huh?
你们怎么能在这么热的地方工作?
How do you work in this heat?
今天算不错的了 我的朋友
You've come on a good day, my friend.
有时候会高达华氏120度(约49℃)
Sometimes it can be 120 degrees
你得见见洛克什博士
I want you to meet Dr. Lokesh.
他是清奈大学的量子物理专家
Fellow of Quantum Physics at the University in Chennai.
(印度合十礼)
- 你好 - 这是赫尔姆斯利博士
- Namaste. - Dr. Helmsley
那么 你要给我看什么?
So, what are we looking at?
这些中微子行为正常
These neutrinos are acting normally.
没有聚集或是带电荷
No mass, no electrical charge.
他们可以不受干扰的穿过其它物质
They pass through ordinary matter almost undisturbed.
你曾告诉我 它们的数量 在上次太阳喷发后翻了一倍?
Your message said the count doubled after the last solar eruptions.
那是上周的事了
That was last week.
现在我要说的是两天前的事
But this happened two days ago.
人类历史上最大的一次太阳喷发
The biggest solar eruptions in human history.
产生的中微子数量 将是有记录以来最多的一回
Causing the highest neutrino count we've ever recorded.
我的天啊
My God.
我担心的并不是这个 艾德里安
That's not what worries me, Adrian.
史无前例的是
For the first time ever,
中微子正在引起物理反应
the neutrinos are causing a physical reaction.
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
真是太爽了!
That feels very good!
走吧 跟我来
Please, follow me.
你不会相信这个的
You won't believe this.
这很诡异
这个水槽还要再深1800米
This water tank goes down another 6000 feet.
看起来 这些来自太阳的中微子
It looks like the neutrinos coming from the sun,
已经突变成了一种新的核粒子
have mutated into a new kind of nuclear particle.
它们正在给地核加热
They're heating up the Earth's core.
然后突然变得就和微波一样
And suddenly act like microwaves.
林肯广场酒店, 华盛顿
女士们先生们 正如我承诺过的
Ladies and gentlemen. As promised:
2009年
没有演说
No speech!
就一句 谢谢各位
Just a "thank you".
今晚多亏了大家的慷慨解囊
Because tonight, with your extraordinary generosity,
我们筹到了170万美元
we have raised 1.7 million dollars.
拜托 别拦我
It's okay.It's okay.
我是白宫的工作人员 - 不管你是谁 先生
- I work for the White House. - I don't care who you are, sir
这是宴会 只有着正装才能进入
This is a black tie event.
斯科蒂!
Scotty!
嘿 艾德里安 我以为你还在印度呢
Hey, Adrian, I thought you were in India
怎么回来了?
What's going on?
- 我需要你的外套 - 什么?
- I need your jacket. - What?
我得和安海斯谈谈
I gotta speak to Anheuser.
- 可是我... - 快给我该死的外套!
- I don't wanna give... - Give me your damn jacket, please!
可以进去了吧?
Okay?
小心点! 这衣服可值600美元
Easy! That's a 600 dollar jacket.
安海斯先生?
Mr. Anheuser?
安海斯先生
Mr. Anheuser.
我需要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
我们认识?
Do I know you?
对不起 我是艾德里安・赫尔姆斯利博士
Sorry sir, my name is Dr. Adrian Helmsley.
我是白宫科技政策办公室的
I'm a deputy geologist at the Office of
副研究员
Science and Technology Policy
失陪一下
Excuse me, fellows.
你应该知道这是个资金筹集酒会
You know that this is a fund-raiser,
不是什么联谊会 好吗?
not a frat party, right?
这件事非常重要 先生
It's extremely important, sir.
事情总是很重要 你看这样行不行
You know what? It always is. Here is what I want you to do:
跟我的秘书约一下见面时间
Make an appointment or even better,
或者最好让你的上司在本季度的科学报告会上再和我说 好吗?
have your boss bring it up at the quarterly science briefing, OK?
凡事要按计划来
There's a good plan.
先生 我飞了20个小时 两天没合眼
I just traveled 20 straight hours to get here, sir.
赶到这里就是要你看看这个 先生
I haven't slept in two days. You need to read this, sir.
你现在就要看!
You need to read it now!
让我猜猜 国家地质危机?
Let me guess. National geology crisis?
失陪!
Excuse me.
谁是你的上司?
Who do you report to?
利科・瓦索斯
Lico Vasos.
不再是了
Not anymore.
艾尔 把车开过来
Al, bring the car around.
- 你先去洗个澡 - 什么?
- You may wish you took a shower. - Sir?
等一会要去见总统
You're about to meet the president.
怎么回事?
What's going on?
把东西放到我办公室去
Get that to the office.
八国集团首脑会议, 英属哥伦比亚
2010年
早上好
Good morning.
我希望与在座的各国元首
I would like to meet privately
进行一次秘密会议
with my fellow heads of state.
我国总统希望他的翻译可以在场
Mr.Macaraca wishes to have his interpreters present.
总统先生 我可以向您保证
Mr. President, I can assure you,
您的英语程度 绝对能听懂我的话
your English is more than sufficient for what I have to say.
出去吧
请坐 总统先生
Mr. President.
半年前
Six months ago,
我得知了一个非常绝望的情报
I was made aware of a situation so devastating
起初 我甚至拒绝相信
that at first I refused to believe it.
然而
However,
在我们最优秀的科学家们的共同努力下
through the concerted efforts of our brightest scientists,
我们已经确认了它的真实性
we have confirmed its validity.
我们所熟知的这个世界
The world as we know it
即将毁灭
will soon come to an end.
卓铭谷, 西藏
2010年
这是一个很好的机会
今后会创造更多的工作机会
党和国家一定会帮助大家重建家园的
奶奶 把手给我
我们去哪儿啊?
别担心 奶奶
走 走
哥哥
奶奶 我会寄钱给你的
谁能够写?
谁能够读?
谁能烧焊?
皇家大酒店, 伦敦
2011年
陛下 想必您已经看过材料了吧
Has His Highness had an opportunity to study the dossier?
要知道 我有很多家人 这位...
You must understand I have a very big family, Mr....
叫我艾萨克斯
Isaacs.
10亿美元可是一大笔钱
One billion dollars is a lot of money.
非常抱歉 陛下
I'm afraid the amount is in Euros,
是10亿欧元
Your Highness.
卢浮宫, 巴黎
2011年
我可是非常信任你们机构的
这真是完美的复制品 罗兰
现在到处都是狂热份子 很可能破坏她
想想那些在阿富汗被炸毁的佛像
我们的遗产机构已经开始
从大英博物馆和东宫博物馆迁移珍品
把她藏在瑞士的隧道里
我相信 她一定会很安全了
绝对安全 罗兰
只有通过红外分析才能看出差别
但这仍是赝品
一个纪录片小组发现了这次集体自杀
This mass suicide was actually discovered by a documentary crew here
这里是玛雅古城 达格尔
in the ancient Mayan city of Takal.
我们看到了许多死者
Now the victims, and we've seen many,
据说他们都相信"玛雅预言"
are said to have adhered to the Mayan-Quiche calender,
"玛雅预言"是说 由于太阳毁灭性的力量
which predicts the end of time to occur on the 21st December of this year,
今年的12月21日 将成为世界末日
due to the suns destructive forces.
谢谢 马克
Thank you, Mark.
神奇的是 科学研究也证明了这一观点
Strangely enough, scientific records do support the fact
曼哈顿海滩, 加利福尼亚州
我们正面临有史以来 最剧烈的太阳活动
that we are heading for the biggest solar climax in recorded history.
许多人相信"玛雅预言"
Many people believe that the Mayan Calender
当太阳系的全部行星排成一条直线...
predicts that there's supposed to be a galactic alignment...
我完蛋了 完蛋了 彻底完蛋了
I'm a dead man. I'm a dead man. I'm a dead man.
嘿 凯特 我已经上高速公路了
Hey, Kate, I'm practically on the freeway right now.
对 我正朝你那边去呢
Yes, I'm rolling towards you as we speak.
别急好不好? 我马上就到了
Would you relax? I'll be there any second.
我们是去玩 又不是去看医生
You know it's a vacation and not a doctors appointment, right?
一定会很好玩的
It's supposed to be fun.
你知道什么是好玩的 是不是?
You remember fun, don't you Kate?
还记得从什么时候开始 你觉得都不好玩了吗?
Do you remember where you were when it stopped being fun for you?
我知道了
Got it.
防蚊液?
Bug spray?
噢 对 这个季节黄石公园的蚊子很多
Oh yeah, cause it's mosquito season in Yellowstone.
我带了很多 先挂了 这里信号不好
I got a whole bunch. I gotta go, because I'm in a bad reception area.
哇哦! 老兄 看到了吗?
Woah, man. Would you look at that?
天啊!
Sick
梅里尔 我跟你说过
Merrill, I told you.
我们应该搬回威斯康星州
We have to move back to Wisconsin.
兰迪 这些小地震真的让我很害怕
These little mini-quakes are really getting on my nerves, Randy.
得了吧 只是地表的一些小裂缝而已 没什么可担心的
Come on, a little surface crack, you're not gonna be inconvenienced by that.
也对 找个整形医生来就可以了
Right, surface cracks, I've got a plastic surgeon for that
哈哈 多亏有防震咖啡杯
Thank God for those shake-proof coffee mugs.
充分展现了加州人的本性
They show the true nature of us Californians.
我们不会向这些小裂缝低头的
We'll not bow to these little inconvenient things like surface quakes.
忏悔吧
因为末日要
降临
引申自《圣经》
你有关于地震的趣事要分享吗?
Do you have a funny mini-quake story and want to share it?
- 嗨 爹地 - 嗨 宝贝
- Hi, daddy! - Hi, baby.
- 甜心 过得好不好? - 很好
- How are you sweety? - Good
- 杰克逊 这是怎么回事? - 别这么叫我
- Jackson, what is this? - Please don't call me that.
我是你爸爸
I'm your dad.
开豪华车带他们去露营?
Taking them camping in a limo?
好极了 很有派头 你的临时工作怎么样了?
Okay, great. What happened to your temp job?
比较闲 不过有更多的时间写作了
Better hours, more time to write.
睡眠呢 你最近还失眠吗?
What about sleeping, have you been doing that lately?
我说过无数次了
I've said it a thousand times.
周五不做抽脂手术 太恶心了
No lipo on Fridays. It's too messy.
等一下
Hold on.
- 早上好 杰克逊 - 嗨
- Morning Jackson. - Hi
- 这车不错 - 谢谢
- Nice ride. - Thanks.
旅途愉快 记住 小心大黑熊
Have a nice trip. Remember, watch out for the bears.
再见 戈登
Bye, Gordon.
- 爱你 亲爱的 - 再见
- Love you, Honey. - Bye
- 那么 什么事? - 你跟他说
- Okay, so, oh,yeah. - You tell him.
跟我说什么?
Tell me what?
每晚睡觉前帮她换上
She needs to put these on every night before she goes to sleep.
还要穿?
Still?
没错 你7岁大的女儿还会尿床
Yes. Your 7 year old daughter still wets her bed.
你从来不关心你的女儿
Maybe that's something you should know.
- 爱你 - 我也爱你 妈妈
- Love you. - Love you, Mom.
- 嘿! - 好了吗?
- Hey! - You okay?
他们早就想和你一起出去玩了
They really were looking forward to spending some time with you
我知道
I know.
所以 不要老泡在电脑上
So don't be on your computer all the time.
知道了
Got it.
我爱你们!
Love you!
- 这次我们要去日本 - 那又怎样?
- So this time we'll hit Japan. - So?
你就能去看看你的儿子威尔了
Now you can visit your boy, Will.
下午好 美女们!
Afternoon, ladies!
你好 帅哥
Hello!
你在听我说话吗?
Are you even listening to me?
听着呢 哈里
Unfortunately I am, Harry.
我听奥德利说 你当爷爷了
I heard from Audrey you're a grandpa now.
能不能不要管我的家务事?
Would you mind keeping your nose out of my family?
别破坏了我的心情 伙计 我们在这儿
You're cramping my style, baby. There we are.
爵士
之夜
哈里
与
托尼
晚上8点
只不过娶个日本媳妇 又不是世界末日
So he married a Japanese girl, how's that the end of the world?
好了 托尼 好歹去看他一次吧
Come on, Tony, you should at least go see him.
- 你去看过你儿子了吗? - 不是经常去
- You see your boy? - Not as much as I'd like.
华盛顿太远了 但起码我们聊电话
DC is a long way, but at least we talk
聊什么?
About what?
人生 人生苦短啊
Life. And how short it is.
见鬼 这是怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
- 喂? - 劳拉?
- Hello? - Laura?
劳拉 你听得见吗?
罗兰 是你吗?
劳拉 我们被骗了
明天我准备开一个记者招待会
我要告诉大家真相
你在说什么?
你拿走的那些艺术品根本不在瑞士
那些隧道都是空的
我有证据
劳拉 劳拉 你听得见吗?
罗兰 我听不到你说什么
劳拉 能听见吗?
∮轮回永不间断
∮永无止境
∮美好的的家园 就在前面
∮在那苍穹
黄石国家公园
- 我喜欢那首歌 - 收不到了
- I liked that song. - We lost it.
西海岸到处都是地表裂缝
The west coast with all those surface cracks,
我告诉自己 "查理 快他妈的去黄石公园"
I told myself, Charlie, get your stupid ass to Yellowstone.
我可不想错过大爆炸
I don't want to miss all the fun when it finally blows.
我爆个料 整个早上 政府的人就在黄石公园上空飞来飞去
Let me tell you, there's been government people flying in and out all morning,
相信我 他们个个都面色凝重
and trust me, they do not look happy.
- 听众们 一定要记住 - 真奇怪
- Always remember, folks. - It's weird.
- 是查理最先告诉你们的 - 你相信他说的?
- You heard it first from Charlie. - Can you believe he said that?
那你相信怪兽吗?
What are the odds?
我们并没有看到土壤像预期的那样液化
We're not seeing the soil liquefaction we'd expect
也没有迹象表明这是板块的裂缝延伸
or find any evidence of fracture propagation within the tectonic plates.
通俗点 博士
English, doctor.
西海岸的那些裂缝不是由板块...
The seismic activity on the west coast is not caused by tect...
不是由正常的地震引起的
by regular earth quakes.
地表的这些裂缝和地球的板块断层无关
And these surface cracks have nothing to do with shifting fault lines.
你是说 现在就要开始实施卓铭计划?
Are you suggesting this could be the beginning of the Joline operation?
赫尔姆斯利博士今天会飞到黄石公园搜集更多资料 总统先生
Dr. Helmsley is flying to Yellowstone this morning to collect more data, sir.
我们一直在按照你制定的时间表进行 赫尔姆斯利博士
We've been following the schedule you established, Mr Helmsley.
人类历史上最重要的时间表
The most important schedule in the history of mankind.
可你却告诉我 这个时间表作废了?
Now you're telling me we have to throw it out?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
是我弄错了
I was wrong.
你知道有谁敢在这间办公室里这样说吗?
Do you know how many times I've heard those words in this office?
一个也没有
Zero.
你看报纸了么?
Did you see this?
对不起 总统先生 她执意要进来
I'm sorry Mr President. She insisted.
新闻上都在播这个
It's all over the news.
我们正在进一步调查这起汽车爆炸事件
We are learning more about this deadly car explosion,
法国国家博物馆馆长
The director of the French National Museum
原定于今早在卢浮宫召开记者招待会
was scheduled to hold a press conference at the Louvre this morning.
巧的是 1997年 戴安娜王妃
Coincidentally, his death took place in the same Paris tunnel
也是在这条隧道中遇难
where Princess Diana died in 1997.
我们会继续追踪报道此事件
We are continuing to follow this story...
劳拉 你没有见过赫尔姆斯利博士吧
Laura, I don't believe you've met Dr. Helmsley.
我和他通过电话 爸爸 他跟我说...
I just talked to him Dad, and he told me...
我工作的机构是一个骗局
the organization I work for is a sham.
他为什么这么说?
Why would he say that?
你生起气来和你妈妈一模一样
You look just like your mother when you get upset.
- 我有和你说过吗? - 每次我生气你都这样说
- Did I ever tell you that? - Every time I get upset.
爸爸 有人被谋杀了
Daddy, a man was killed.
亲爱的 先坐下
Honey. Please sit down.
我将要告诉你的事 即使在白宫也只有十几个人知道
Only a dozen people in this administration know what I'm about to tell you.
爸爸 到底发生了什么事?
Dad, what's going on?
我们正在进行一次史无前例的 国际合作
An unprecedented international endeavor is under way.
目前已经有46个国家参与
At this point 46 nations are invested in this thing.
劳拉很聪明 她会明白的
Laura's a smart girl. She'll understand.
巴黎的那件事
That thing in Paris.
与我们无关 对吧?
We're not involved in any of that, are we?
"我们"? "我们"是什么鬼东西?
"We"? Who the hell is "we"?
你在说什么啊?
What are you talking about?
我们的当务之急是这个时间表
What we need to do is focus on this time line. That's we need to do.
那什么时候告诉大家真相?
So when do we let the country know?
- 什么意思? - 我们的百姓啊 长官
- What do you mean? - The people, sir.
他们有权知道
They need to know.
他们当然会知道 听好了
Well of course they do. Listen.
你的任务是弄清楚 地球什么时候毁灭
Your job is to figure out when this is all gonna fall apart.
我的任务是设法在世界毁灭后 维持政府的存在
My job is to figure out how to retain some type of government after it falls apart.
现在我们没时间管别的 懂了吗?
Until then we don't have time for anything except those jobs. Okay?
- 黄石公园那边有什么消息立刻告诉我 - 知道了
- You call me when you have any news from Yellowstone. - Yes Sir
- 很靓吧? - 什么?
- Cute girl, huh? - Sir?
第一千金啊 我看到你盯着她看了
The First Daughter, I saw you looking at her.
- 我没有 - 动作快点 孩子
- I wasn't looking at her. - Better move fast kid
世界末日快到了
The end is near.
艾德里安 你的直升机准备好了
Adrian, your chopper's ready.
他们正在白宫南草坪等你
They're waiting on the south lawn.
- 爹地 我们这是去哪儿? - 去一个很特别的地方
- Daddy, where are we going? - Going to a really special place I know.
以前我和妈妈经常去那里
Actually, it's a place where your mom and I used to hang out a lot.
我可不想去你和妈妈亲热的地方
I don't want to know where you and mom had sex.
我还太小了 杰克逊
I'm not ready for that, Jackson.
别这样叫我 这让我很不舒服
Stop calling me that, it's creeping me out.
叫我"爸爸"这么难吗?
What's wrong with "Dad"?
爹地 快看
Daddy, look at this.
以前这里没有围起来
That wasn't here before.
怎么办?
What did I do?
我去捡帽子
Go get your hat.
禁区    警告
你们没看见警告吗?
Don't you see the signs?
以前这里是个湖
There used to be a lake here.
怎么看都不像是湖
Doesn't look much of a lake to me.
我知道 整个湖都不见了
I know. The whole damn thing's gone.
来吧 我们去看看怎么回事
Come on, let's check it out.
好极了
Great.
目标进入热区
Subjects have now entered hot zone.
他们是谁?
Who is that?
美国陆军
It's the U.S. Army.
政府部队正向目标接近
All manner of government vehicle are converging on subjects.
这里是禁区 先生
You're in a restricted area, sir.
你和你的家人请跟我们走
We need you and your family to come with us.
好的 现在我们跟这些人走
Right. Okay, we're gonna go with these guys.
很好玩 对吧?
That'll be fun, huh?
太疯狂了 实在是太疯狂了
This is wild. This is really wild.
简直不敢相信 地下12千米 温度2700度?
This is unbelievable. 2700℃ at 40,000 feet?
我知道 这听起来不可思议
I know, it sounds completely implausible.
但温度确实在以0.5%的幅度上升
Nonetheless, we're noticing an increase of almost 0.5%
- 每天? - 不是
- Per day? - No.
每小时
Per hour.
赫尔姆斯利博士 我们从热区抓回了3个游客
Dr. Helmsley, we arrested some tourists in the hot zone.
我来处理吧
I'll take care of it.
你去跟萨特南联系
Let's get Satnam on the communications link.
对比一下这些数据
Try to cross reference the data.
这里是国家公园 不该有围栏吧?
It's a national park, there's not supposed to be fences, right?
我的意思是 发生什么事了?
I mean, what's going on here?
我们是地质学家
We're geologists.
你们用机关枪挖地?
You usually go digging with machine guns?
少校 我来处理就好 谢谢!
Major, I'll take care of this, thank you.
那个湖怎么了?
So, what happened to the lake?
这正是我们要调查的
Well, that's what we're trying to find out.
我们发现这里变得很不稳定
We think the entire area has become unstable.
你应该带着你的孩子离开这里
I think you should take your kids and leave, Mr....
柯蒂斯先生
Curtis.
你该不会就是《再见亚特兰蒂斯》的作者 杰克逊・柯蒂斯吧?
You're not by any chance the Jackson Curtis who wrote "Farewell Atlantis"?
正是在下
The very same.
那本书是献给我妈妈的
It's actually dedicated to my mom.
我大学时读过一些你的短篇小说
I read a couple of your short stories in college.
- 你爸爸是个很有才华的人 - 听到了吧
- Your father is a very, very talented man. - Listen up.
真巧 我正在读你的书
It's amazing. I'm reading your book.
看到第300天 太空船与地球失去了联系
I'm around day 300, the shuttle has just lost communication with Earth.
很少有人买这本书
You're one of the lucky few who bought it.
- 我没买 - 没买?
- I didn't buy it. - No?
我老爸送我的
My dad gave it to me.
我想问你一些事
Let me ask you something.
你真的相信在生死关头
Do you think those people would behave so selflessly
人们会那么无私吗?
knowing that their own lives were at stake?
我希望是
I hope so.
评论家说我太天真 是个幼稚的乐观主义者
The critics said I was naive, an unabashed optimist,
可他们又懂什么呢 对吧?
but what do they know, right?
- 很荣幸认识你 - 我也是
- It was a great pleasure meeting you. - Thank you.
少校 麻烦您把他们送到露营区
Mayor, could you escort these good people to the camp grounds, please.
- 这是你的 - 对
- This is yours. - Yeah.
- 谢谢 - 是 长官
- Thank you. - Yes, sir.
- 保重 - 好的
- Take care. - Okay
他人不错
He was very nice.
你这样说是因为他喜欢我的书吧
You're just saying that cause he likes my book.
看来你儿子会比我们都聪明
Looks like that boy of yours is gonna be smarter than any of us.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
我把温度数据发给他了
I sent Satnam the temperature readings.
你的数据 与我在阿根廷和安大略的同事测到的数据 几乎一样
My colleagues in Argentina and Ontario have almost identical data.
这里太热 我们只好把铜矿井封了
It's so hot here we've had to seal off the mine.
- 你仔细检查过数据了吗? - 我检查了3遍 我的朋友
- Did you double check the numbers? - I triple checked, my friend.
我希望是我们弄错了 但是 事实就是这样
I wish we were wrong, but, we're not.
地壳越来越不稳定了
The Earth's crust is destabilizing.
- 这太快了 - 艾德里安 你们必须开始撤离了
- It's too early. - Adrian. You have to begin the evacuation.
天啊
My God.
什么高科技 先进的设备
All our scientific advances, our fancy machines,
玛雅人几千年前就预测到了
the Mayans saw this coming thousands of years ago.
我以为还有很多时间
I thought we'd have more time.
好 我要你和家人赶快收拾行李
Okay, I want you to pack up your family.
我会安排飞机到新德里接你们
I'm gonna arrange an airlift from Delhi.
谢谢你 我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.
祝我们好运
And good luck.
阿吉特
Ajit.
我们要去坐大船了
We are going on a big ship.
等等 等等 等一等
Wait. Wait, wait. Wait
打扰了 就一个问题
Sorry. One question.
政府的人跟你们说了什么?
What did the government guys say to you?
说我们不该翻越围栏
They don't like us going over their fences and
还说这整个区域很不稳定
that the whole area back there is unstable.
"不稳定"? 他们说"不稳定"?
"Unstable"? They said "unstable"?
- 很好笑 哈哈哈 - 我们走
- That's funny. - Let's go.
"不稳定" 哈哈哈
"Unstable".
不只是黄石公园 长官
It's not just Yellowstone, sir.
全球所有热区的温度
Temperatures are rising with incredible velocity
都在急剧上升
in hot zones across the globe.
艾德里安 你百分之百的确定吗?
Are you absolutely sure about this, Adrian?
一旦命令发布 就无法撤销了 你明白的
Because once we give these orders, there's no going back. You understand that.
恐怕没有时间犹豫了 长官
I'm afraid there's no longer any doubt, sir.
我们得尽可能的多救人
We have to save what we can.
我们得马上撤离
And we have to move now!
黄 石 国 家 公 园
政府管制区
这里好多蚊子 你没带防蚊液吗?
There's mosquitoes in here. Did anybody spray the tent?
我明天就去买
I'm gonna get that spray tomorrow.
蚊子喜欢你 是因为你的血太甜了
They just like you because your blood's so sweet.
爹地 你说过不写书的
Dad, you said you wouldn't work on your book.
什么?
What?
我没写书 我在做别的事
I'm not, I'm not. I'm doing something else.
好吧
Okay.
你真需要这么多帽子吗?
Did you really need all these hats?
你的那个东西呢?
Where are your pull-ups?
我已经穿上了
I have them on.
谁给你的 妈妈?
Who gave you this? Mommy?
不 这是戈登送我的生日礼物
No, Gordon gave it to me for my birthday.
买手机应该经过家庭讨论吧
A cell phone is something we got to talk about. You know, as a family.
什么家庭啊?
What family?
你这么说让我很伤心
It hurts my feelings when you say stuff like that.
大人也会伤心的
Adults get hurt feelings too.
嘿！戈登， 露营糟透了！
不可能
No way.
你是唯一敢说出真相的人
You're brave to tell the truth.
谢谢你 比尔 你有什么问题?
Thank you, Bill. What is your question?
我想知道这一切会从哪里开始?
I wanted to know, where is all this gonna start?
一般这都是好莱坞的好戏
Well, something like this could only originate in Hollywood Bill.
不过说真的 加州的地面已经在开裂了
But, they have the earth cracking under their asses already.
我们全家都信仰耶稣
Our family believes in the gospel of the lord Jesus.
我们无所畏惧 查理
We have nothing to fear, Charlie.
那太好了 比尔 感谢你的来电
Good for you, Bill. Thanks for calling.
我是查理・弗罗斯特 在黄石公园为您现场直播
This is Charlie Frost reporting live from Yellowstone National Park,
这里马上将成为世界上最大的活火山
soon to become the world's largest active volcano.
朋友们 马上回来
I'll be right back, folks.
介意我打扰下吗?
Do you mind if I join you?
我想问你点事
I wanted to ask you something.
我时间不多 吃泡菜吗?
I only got a minute. Pickle?
不了
No
我刚在收听你的节目 我好奇的是
I was listening to the broadcast and I was wondering
到底是什么会从好莱坞开始?
what exactly is it that's gonna start in Hollywood?
是末世 世界末日
It's the Apocalypse. End of days.
审判日 世界末日 我的朋友
The Judgment Day. The end of the world, my friend.
基督徒称之为"被提时刻" 但玛雅人很早就预言了
Christians call it The Rapture, but the Mayans knew about it.
霍皮人 易经 圣经也都说过
The Hopis, the I Ching, the Bible, kind of.
- 要啤酒吗? - 好
- Beer? - Yeah.
你看 我得吃饭了
So look, I gotta eat.
你何不到我的博客里下载呢?
Why don't you download my blog?
免费的 当然我们也欢迎捐款
It's free. Of course, we do appreciate donations.
数千年前 玛雅文明最先发现
In ancient times, the Mayan people were the first civilization to discover that
地球是有期限的
this planet had an expiration date.
根据他们的历法 2012年将会有毁灭性的灾难降临
According to their calender, in the year 2012 a cataclysmic event will unfold,
因为太阳系的全部行星排成一条直线
caused by an alignment of the planets in our solar system
这种现象每64万年才发生一次
that only happens every 640,000 years.
噢 别又来了
Oh, not again.
不错吧? 这动画都是我自己做的
Neat, huh? I did all the animation myself.
把地球想象成一个橙子
Just imagine the earth as an orange.
先用幽默吸引他们
You lure them in with humor.
然后让他们去思考
Then you make them think.
太阳将释放出大量的射线
Our sun will begin to emit such extreme amounts of radiation,
钉死你个浑蛋 来点中微子吧
Screw you bastards. Do you call neutrinos?
首先 地心开始熔化
That the core of the earth will melt at the inside part of the orange.
然后地壳就可以自由移动
Leaving the crust of our planet free to shift.
1958年 查尔斯・哈普古德教授 将此理论命名为 "地壳漂移"
In 1958 Professor Charles Hapgood named it:"Earth Crust Displacement".
阿尔伯特・爱因斯坦也支持这个理论
Albert Einstein did support it.
人类将完全感受到
People will get it all.
地球母亲的毁灭性力量
The forces of Mother Nature will be so devastating.
世界末日就在2012年12月21日冬至那天
It will bring an end to this world on winter Solstice 12-21-12.
听众们要记住 是查理・弗罗斯特最先告诉你们的
Always remember, folks. You heard it first from Charlie Frost.
政府会想法设法保守这个秘密
You'd have to keep a thing like this under wraps.
道理很简单
I mean, just think about it.
首先 股市会崩盘
First, the stock market would go.
然后 经济崩溃 嘣!
Then the economy: Boom!
美元狂跌 嘣!
The dollar: Boom!
还有街头骚乱
And then pandemonium in the street.
战争 种族灭绝 嘣! 嘣! 嘣!
War, genocide. Boom! Boom! Boom!
胡说 没人能守得住这么大的秘密 查理
Bullshit. Nobody could keep that big a secret, Charlie.
一定会有人说出来的
Somebody would blow the whistle
没错 每过一段时间就会有可怜虫想说出来
An every once in a while, some poor little sucker tries.
就像这些家伙 嘣! 嘣!
Like these guys. Boom! Boom!
所有这些人 死了! 死了! 死了!
Every one of these guys. Dead! Dead! Dead!
等等 这是梅耶教授
Woah, that's Professor Meyers.
他负责亚特兰蒂斯宇宙飞船计划 你认识他?
He ran the Atlantis Shuttle Program. Did you know him?
对 写书时他帮了我很多
Yeah, he helped me out with research on my book.
那一定是在他出事之前
Well, that must have been before his accident.
- 梅耶教授死了? - 对 两个月前
- Meyers is dead? - Yeah, two months ago.
他是我的狂热听众之一
He was one of my most avid listeners.
他全都弄清楚了
He had it all figured out.
政府在做什么 怎么做 在哪里
Everything the government was doing, where, why.
他甚至寄给我一张地图
He even sent me a map.
什么地图 查理? 什么地图?
A map for what, Charlie? What's the map for?
他们在造太空船 伙计
They're building space ships, man.
胡扯 我得走了 我要回地球去了
Shit, man, I have to go. Because, I gotta get back to Earth.
- 你还有啤酒吗? - 这是最后一罐
- Do you have a beer? - This is my last.
好吧 我真是大开眼界了
Alright, anyway, I really enjoyed most of this.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
知道吗? 他们在卖座位!
Guess what, they're selling seats!
给我留三张
Put me down for three.
不可能 像我们这种普通人是没有机会的
No! Guys like you and me don't have any chance.
除非是你比尔・盖茨 默多克 或者俄罗斯的亿万富翁才行
You'd have to be Bill Gates or Rupert Murdoch, or some Russian billionaire.
小点声 我的孩子睡着了
Keep it down, my kids are sleeping.
快带他们离开黄石公园 这里很危险
Get them out of Yellowstone. It's gonna get ugly here.
我们生个孩子吧?
Why don't we make a baby?
在超市里可没办法生孩子
We're not making a baby at the supermarket.
嘿 快把手拿开
Hands off the merchandise.
亲爱的 别的女人要我摸她们的胸部要花好几千块钱
Honey, woman give me thousands of dollars to handle their boobs.
你可是免费的
You get it for free.
每次见过他后 你都会很反常
You always act strange after he shows up.
我没有反常 我只是在找通心粉
I'm not acting strange, I'm looking for macaroni.
你怎么会和他在一起这么久呢?
So why did you stick with him so long anyways?
不说这个可以吗?
Can we just give it a rest, please?
- 他是孩子的父亲 - 算了吧, 凯特
- He's the father of my children. - Oh, come on, Kate
为了生诺亚 你放弃了去医学院深造
You gave up med school so you could have Noah.
你一个人辛苦的把诺亚和莉莉带大
You practically raised him and Lilly by yourself
可他却只会呆呆的坐在电脑前写那些垃圾
while he sat glued to a laptop writing that junk.
那不是垃圾 已经出版了
It's not junk! He's published.
对 我忘了 是出版了
Oh, published. Right, I forgot.
卖了422本
422 copies.
- 你看见了吗? - 看见什么?
- Did you see that? - See what?
凯特 听着 我们必须要改善
Kate, listen, we have to keep working at this.
我们之间的关系
Our relationship.
亲爱的 我总感觉有什么东西要将我们分开
I don't know, Honey, I feel like there's something pulling us apart.
抓住那柱子 凯特 别放手 坚持住
Hold on! Grab the pole! Kate, don't let go!
有对付蚊虫叮咬的药吗?
Do you have anything for mosquito bites?
驱蚊还是治包?
Before or after?
两种都拿给你
I'll get before and after.
别挠了 不然会感染的
Stop scratching or you're gonna get it all infected.
看 是伯恩鲍姆太太
Look. It's Mrs Birnbaum.
她是我的老师 她上电视了
She's my teacher. She's on TV!
当时超市正在营业
The market which was open for business at the time
不过幸好没有伤亡报告
but fortunately there are no fatalities or injuries reported.
真是个奇迹 竟然没有人受伤
It really is a miracle that no one got hurt.
你好? 嗨 妈妈
Hello? Hi mom.
你看到我们家附近的超市发生什么了吗?
Did you see what happened to our supermarket?
她要我们都回家
She wants us to come home.
这不是真的吧?
Is this even possible?
我们整晚都在策划可行的方案
We worked every option through the night.
好消息是 有4艘方舟可以及时启用
The good news: consensus is that 4 of the Arks will be operational in time.
只有4艘 这还算好消息?
Only 4? You call that good news?
我们可以救超过40万人
We can save over 400,000 people.
总统先生 对我来说 这几乎是奇迹了
To me, sir, that's nothing short of a miracle.
但我们必须立刻启动登船程序
But we have to initiate the boarding process now.
托马斯 我们别无选择
Thomas. We don't have a choice.
你一定要说服他们
You have got to convince them.
根据黄石公园传来的最新消息
According to the latest information from Yellowstone.
- 请继续 艾德里安 - 好的 总统先生
- Please continue, Adrian. - Thank you, sir.
地球的地壳
The temperature of the subterranean crust,
也就是大陆板块连接的地方
that is the cement that holds our landmass in place,
温度正在急剧上升 远在意料之外
is increasing at a rapid rate much faster than anticipated.
这导致地球的两极很不稳定
As a result we've observed extreme polar instability
在过去的48小时里 磁场面积已减少超过80%
The magnetic fields have decreased by more than 80% in the last 48 hours.
我们还有多少时间 赫尔姆斯利博士?
How much time do we have, Dr. Helmsley?
两天 运气好的话 可能三天
Two, maybe three days, if we're lucky.
这种情况下 怎么还能靠运气?
How can you speak about luck in such a situation?
对不起 总理先生
Apologies, Mr. Prime Minister.
我没有不敬的意思
I meant no disrespect.
恐怕我们拖得越久 运气越远离我们
I'm afraid the longer we wait, the more luck plays its part.
我的朋友们
My friends.
我建议 立即开始撤离
I recommend we evacuate immediately.
如果谁反对
If any of you have objections
请现在提出来
Please speak now.
在蓝色角落的是 38次胜利 34次击倒对手
In the blue corner, 38 victories, 34 knockouts,
来自乌克兰的战斗机器
the fighting machine from the Ukraine,
战无不胜的头号重量级挑战者
the undefeated number one ranked heavyweight challenger:
祖尔坦・巴拉辛
Mr. Zultan Balashin!
- 尤里先生 - 祖尔坦
- Yuri! - Zultan!
我还担心您不来了呢
他需要集中精神 卡尔波夫先生
He needs to concentrate now, Mr. Karpov.
我跟他说话时 闭上你的嘴 懂吗?
You shut up while I talk to my boy, understand?
- 是 卡尔波夫先生 - 好 非常好
- Yes, Mr Karpov. - Good. That is good.
祖尔坦 听着
我们是战士 永远不能倒下
不管敌人有多么强
宰了那浑蛋
Kill the bastard.
让我们尽情呐喊吧!
Let's get ready to rumble!
祖尔坦 加油!
狠狠的打 给我狠狠的打
登录
指纹验证
注意
启动
登船
程序
尤里 你去哪儿?
尤里!
加州理工学院称 韦斯特伍德地区的地裂
CalTech believes that the fissures running through Westwood
已经释放了大部份地表张力
has released most of the surface tension.
"我们的生活很快就会恢复正常" 市长冈萨雷斯如是说
Life in the city will soon return to normal, Mayor Gonzales said.
好了 小家伙 快到家了
Okay guys. Almost home.
醒醒吧
Rise and shine.
好啦 到家了
Alright, you're free.
妈咪!
Mommy!
我的宝贝
Hi, sweetheart.
戈登
Gordon!
嘿 小伙子
Hey, buddy boy.
玩得开心吗? 我真想你
Had a good time, yeah? God, I missed you.
- 谁想吃煎饼? 快来 - 我!
- Who wants pancakes? Come on.- Me!
- 谢谢你提早送他们回来 - 不客气
- Thanks for bringing them home early. - Yeah.
吃煎饼吗?
Pancakes?
待会还要工作
Late for work.
- 喂 你好? - 柯蒂斯 你在哪儿?
- Yes, hello? - Curtis, where are you?
- 刚休完假回来 先生 - 好 非常好
- Just back from vacation, sir. - Good. That is good.
我会派飞机去接亚力克和奥列格
I will send a jet to pick up Alec and Oleg.
尤里 告诉他给凯撒(狗狗名)带雨衣
Yuri bear, tell him to bring the rain coat for Caesar.
在那辆路虎里
It's in the Range Rover.
- 柯蒂斯? - 是
- Curtis? - Yeah
尽快去接我儿子
Get my boys as fast as you can.
我正在赶着去那儿 先生
I'm hurling towards you as we speak, sir.
好 非常好
Good. That is good.
- 柯蒂斯 你迟到了 - 早啊你们两个
- Curtis, you're late. - Good morning to you two.
你小心点放
Be careful with our stuff.
别弄脏了 白痴
Don't get your dirt on it. Idiot.
怎么这么久 柯蒂斯先生?
Took you a while, Mr. Curtis.
你脑子进水了吗? 小心点!
What's your problem? Be more careful.
他故意的
He did that on purpose.
一路平安 两个小混蛋
Have a safe trip, you little bastards.
你笑吧 柯蒂斯
Now you're laughing, Curtis.
我们有票能上大船
But we have tickets to go on a big ship.
我们能够活命 你就等死吧
We will leave, and you will die.
胡说什么! 赶快上来 要迟到了
你们听到了吗? 洛杉矶当局竟然说
Did you hear that? The authorities in L.A.
这没什么可担心的
say there's nothing to worry about.
我倒想看看当马布里和比佛利山庄
I'd love to see their faces
沉到太平洋里时 他们是啥表情
when Malibu and Beverly Hills sink down into the Pacific.
看他们的电车还怎么充电
Where will they plug in their electric cars then?
- 这是你的飞机吗? - 是
- Is this your plane? - Yeah
- 你是飞行员吗? - 是
- Are you a pilot? - Yeah
我想租这飞机 行吗?
I want to rent it, okay?
你要什么我都给你 这块手表很昂贵的 给你
I'll give anything you want. Here, take this very expensive watch.
我邻居送的 他那时以为我会成为大人物
My neighbor gave it to me when he thought I was gonna be somebody.
经加州理工学院确认 在过去的36小时中
...CalTech, that in the last 36 hours we have
加州南部几乎没有发生任何地震
basically zero earthquake activity in Southern California,
大家无需担心
which is very rare.
这和我在电影里演的角色不同...
Unlike the tough characters I have portrayed in my films...
你好?
Hello?
- 凯特 停下你手头上的事情 - 杰克逊?
- Kate, stop what you're doing. - Jackson?
听我说 我租了架飞机 让孩子们收拾好
Listen to me. I've rented a plane, pack up the kids,
5分钟内我就到
I'm gonna be there in 5 minutes.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
我们会像平常一样过周末
We're gonna have a regular Saturday.
诺亚两点上音乐课 莉莉要学空手道
Noah has music at 2:00 and Lilly has karate.
你指望他能记住这些?
You expect him to remember?
凯特 加州就要沉没了!
Kate, California is going down.
- 马上带孩子们出来 - 他们刚到家
- Pack up the kids now! - They just got back.
天啊 你听起来像个疯子
God, you sound like a crazy person.
州长刚说过 我们很安全
The governor just said we're fine now.
那家伙是个演员 他在念台词
The guy's an actor, he's reading a script!
他说一切正常时 就代表该逃命了
When they tell you not to panic, that's when you run!
等你冷静后再打给我好吗?
Will you call me back when you calm down?
妈咪 你干嘛那么生气?
Mommy, why are you acting so crazy?
吃你的煎饼 宝贝
Finish your pancakes, Al Capone.
在我来看 最糟糕的时刻已经过去了
It seems to me that the worst is over.
拉住妈妈的手!
Hold Mommy's hands!
- 快走 快走 - 我觉得这下面比较安全
- Let's go! Let's go! - I think it's safer under here!
赶紧给我他妈的上车!
Get in the fucking car!
快走 孩子们!
Come on, kids!
上车 赶快上车
Get in. Get in.
我的帽子
My hats!
抓紧了!
Buckle up!
抱歉
Sorry.
杰克逊 快点 小心后面
Jackson. Hurry up! Look behind you!
天啊
Oh God.
- 快让开 - 让开
- Get out of the way! - Move it!
小心鸡蛋 亲爱的
Hold on, dear.
快点 老太婆!
Come on, you old bags!
大家坐稳了
Everybody hangs on.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
臭死了
Stink.
我们得赶到圣莫妮卡机场
We gotta get to Santa Monica Airport.
上高速 能节省一半时间
Take the freeway. It'll be half the time.
对 没错
Yeah, right.
我们得走高速的另一边了
We gotta get to the other side of the freeway.
爸爸 小心!
Dad, look!
哈佛大学测算 地震强度达10.9级
They've just been upgraded to a 10.9 by Harvard.
加州理工这回没话说了吧?
What does CalTech have to say?
整个帕萨迪娜区毁灭了
The city of Pasadena was wiped out.
就在几分钟前
Just a few minutes ago.
这是科奇拉峡谷的现场画面 就在约书亚树公园附近
This is coming in live from Coachella Valley near Joshua Tree.
今天早上还没有这个大峡谷的
That huge canyon, it wasn't there this morning.
往北100英里的雷斯角公园也一样
100 miles further North, same thing.
- 圣安德烈亚斯断层正在移动 - 是的
- The San Andreas Fault is shifting. - Yes.
加州海湾地区的其它断层也一样
And all major sister faults in the bay area.
整个太平洋板块正在瓦解
The whole Pacific Plate is destabilizing.
快点!
Come on!
- 这是谁? - 我们的飞行员
- Who's that? - Our pilot.
飞行员死了
Dead pilot!
戈登 你会开飞机!
Gordon! Gordon! You can fly!
我只上过几节单引擎飞机驾驶课
No, no. I've only had a couple of lessons in a single engine plane only.
- 戈登 你去驾驶 - 不不 我不行
- You're the guy! - No, no, I'm not the guy!
相信我 你能行
Trust me! You're the guy.
我不是在谦虚!
I'm not being modest about this!
快点 孩子们
Come on, kids.
戈登要带我们离开这里
Gordon's gonna get us out of here.
这飞机是双引擎的
That plane has multiple engines.
杰克逊!
Jackson!
- T和P T和P - TNP? 什么?
- T's and P's, T and P. - TNP? What?
温度与压力
Temperatures and Pressures
- 快飞吧 - 我在作飞行前检查
- Let's go! - My preflight check
让他集中精力 杰克逊 他没有经验
Let him concentrate, Jackson. He has no experience.
谢谢你
Thank you.
戈登! 快走!
Gordon! Go!
加速 快加速!
Go go go!
速度不够
We're not there yet.
- 快起飞 - 速度要达到85节才能起飞
- Punch it! - We need 85 knots.
- 80就够了 - 我们起飞
- 80 is good! - Let's do it.
好了 好了 我们起飞了
Okay, okay, we're up.
莉莉 去你哥哥那儿坐着
Lilly, go sit with your brother.
你怎么知道会发生这些事?
How did you know this would happen?
不只是加州
It's not just California.
全世界都要完蛋了
The whole damn world is going to shit.
我在黄石公园遇到个疯狂的家伙
I met this guy in Yellowstone, he's a crazy guy.
但到目前为止 他全说中了
But he's been right about everything so far.
他还说政府在建造大船
He said the government is building these ships,
太空船之类的东西 我也不知道是什么
space ships, I don't know what, but something.
- 太空船? - 没错 上了船我们就安全了
- Space ships? - Yeah. Places where we could be safe.
他知道太空船在哪儿 他有地图
He knows where they are. He's got a map.
- 杰克逊 - 凯特 这次你一定要相信我
- Jackson... - Kate, trust me on this.
伙计们 快看
Guys. Look.
∮ 但这不是世界末日 伙计
But it ain't the end of the world, Buddy.
∮ 这只是歌曲的结尾
It's only the end of this song.
∮ 这是有趣难忘的经历 是一段惊险的旅程
It's been a gas, been a flip, been a hell of a trip,
∮ 但这不是世界末日
But it ain't the end of the world.
噢耶!
Oh yeah!
- 谢谢 - 你有粉丝了 托尼
- Thank you. - You got fans, Tony.
有电话找你 哈里 要对方留言吗?
There's a call for you, Harry. Want me to take a message?
不用了 凯文 我去接
No, it's OK, Kevin. I'll get it.
你好?
Yeah, hello?
- 爸爸 - 艾德里安
- Dad. - Adrian!
还记得我和你提过的那个中国大坝吗?
Remember I told you about that dam in China?
- 记得 - 真的发生了 爸爸
- Yeah. - It's happening, Dad.
如果他们知道我告诉了你 会杀了我的
They'd probably shoot me if they knew I told you.
没人会杀你 儿子 他们需要你
Nobody's gonna shoot you, son. They need you.
总统已经下令撤离白宫
The President has ordered us to clear out the White House.
早该有人收拾残局了
About time somebody cleaned up that mess.
你在哪儿 爸爸?
Where are you, Dad?
创世纪号现在具体在什么方位?
What exactly is the course of The Genesis right now?
一切都很好 艾德里安
It's all good, Adrian.
别为你老爸担心
Don't you be worrying about your old man.
你有更重要的事情要做
You have more important things to do now.
你知道
You know.
你妈妈和我
Your mom and I.
这辈子过得很美好 儿子
We had one hell of a great life, son.
而其中最棒的是 我们有一个最优秀的孩子
And the best part about that is we had one hell of a great kid, too.
看看这
Look at here.
创世纪号是一艘相当大的船 儿子
This Genesis is a pretty big ship, son.
别以为你老爸死定了
Don't you write your old man off just yet.
而且
Besides.
你知道我不会丢下托尼一个人的
You know I couldn't leave Tony alone.
没有我 这个老笨蛋肯定会走音的
That old fool can't keep decent time by himself.
我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你 儿子 天地可鉴
I love you too, son. God knows I do.
凯文 给我来双份的
Kevin. I want a double.
- 哈里 - 我需要来杯酒
- Harry. - I need a double right now.
谢谢你 孩子
Thank you, son.
你都戒酒25年了 你疯了吗?
After 25 year on the wagon. Are you out of your mind?
- 你要做什么? - 下去
- What are you doing? - Gotta go.
这是违反飞行规定的
That's against regulation!
- 还有油吗? - 有 有油
- Anything? - Yeah, there's fuel.
加满油 我去找查理
Fill her up, I'm gonna go find Charlie.
爹地 等等 我要跟你一起去!
Daddy, wait, I wanna come with you!
回来 莉莉 别去
No, Lil! No! No!
没关系 我带着她
It's alright, I'll take her.
把油加满 我们马上回来
Just fill it up. I'll be right back.
杰克逊 抓紧时间!
Jackson, hurry please!
我正站在
I'm standing here at the highest point
大角山的最高点
of what is the rim of the worlds
对面就是世界最大的超级火山
largest super volcano, Mount Big Horn.
查理
Charlie!
我只能希望 上帝保佑你们
I can only hope that all of you have made your peace.
- 肯定就在这里 - 爹地 我们回去吧
- It's gotta be around here somewhere. - Let's go back, Daddy.
不不不 我们得找到查理 因为他有地图
No, no, no. We gotta find Charlie, cause he's got a map.
就像是海盗电影里的藏宝图
It's like a secret map. Like in pirate movies.
我们现在就是夺宝奇兵 好吗?
We gotta work as a team, okay?
- 好 - 好 我们快走
- Okay. - Okay, come on.
给妈妈打电话 说我们晚五分钟到
Call Mom. Tell her we're gonna be 5 minutes late.
- 你好? - 让妈妈接电话
- Hello? - I need to talk to Mommy.
- 是莉莉 - 宝贝 你在哪里?
- It's Lilly. - Sweet heart, where are you?
- 嗨 妈咪 - 让爸爸听电话
- Hi, Mommy. - Let me speak to Daddy,sweety.
他现在不能说话 他正开得飞快
He cant talk right now. He's driving really really fast.
- 啊! - 莉莉?
- Ouch! - Lilly?
那是谁? 谁在车里说话?
Who is that? Who's speaking in the car?
他不在车上 他在山上等着看焰火呢
He's not in the car, he's on a mountain waiting for fireworks.
焰火? 什么焰火?
Fireworks? What fireworks?
爹地 爹地 看那儿!
Daddy, Daddy, over there.
干得好! 莉莉
Good job, Lilly. Good job.
现在让我跟妈妈说话
Let me talk to mom now.
- 嘿 找到他了 - 杰克逊 快把我的孩子带回来!
- Hey! We got him. - Jackson, bring back my child now!
你留在这里 我去跟海盗谈判 好吗?
You stay here. I will go talk to the pirate, okay?
这一刻 不论你是谁 是穷是富
不论你在哪个国家 什么种族 什么信仰
明天我们都没有区别
查理
Charlie!
你怎么在这儿? 我以为你已经死了
What are you doing? I thought you were toast.
不 我没死 太空船在哪儿?
No no no! Where are the space ships?
你没法赶到那儿的
There is no way you can make it there.
我们有飞机 你可以跟我们一起
We have a plane. You can come with us.
不过我们要马上离开
But we gotta leave right now!
飞吧 小鸟们!
Fly, birdies!
这是你的孩子?
Is this your kid?
- 那该死的地图在哪儿? - 我正在直播呢
- Where's the god damn map? - It's online.
- 我知道 地图在哪儿 - 是个狂热的粉丝
- I know, where is it. - It's a crazy fan.
查理 想想地图在哪儿!
Where's the map?
- 在露营车里 - 在露营车的哪里?
- It's in the camper. - Where in the camper?
地图在"谋反"书架上 杜威图书分类法
Map section. On the conspiracy shelf. Dewey Decimal System.
在罗斯威尔
Between Roswell
和玛丽莲・梦露之间?
and Marilyn Monroe?
演出开始了
It's starting.
你真的不跟我们一起走?
You sure you don't wanna come with me?
太美了 我要留下来
So beautiful, I'm gonna stay.
祝你好运
Good luck.
这是美利坚合众国的最后一天
This marks the last day of the United States of America.
也是全人类的最后一天
Final hour of all mankind.
我们都将成为银河里的一粒微尘
As we will be visible from the Milky Way as a tiny little puff of smoke.
大地正在我眼前土崩瓦解
I'm watching the Earth crumble before my eyes.
超级火山产生的巨大火山灰
The giant ash cloud created by this super volcano
首先将笼罩拉斯维加斯
will first envelop Vegas,
然后是圣路易斯
and then St. Louis
接着是芝加哥
and then Chicago,
最后 华盛顿的灯火也将熄灭
and then at long last, Washington D.C. will have its lights go out.
他疯了 是吧 爹地?
That guy is crazy, right, Daddy?
我想不是
I don't think so.
搞什么飞机
This is ridiculous.
都半个多小时了
It's been over half an hour.
- 那家伙搞什么 - 别说了
- The guy is a nut job. - Stop it.
诺亚 电话给我
Noah, give me the phone again.
爹地 那是什么?
Daddy. What was that?
没事 没什么
Nothing. Nothing.
我都起鸡皮疙瘩了 朋友们!
I have goosebumps, people!
多希望你们也能亲眼目睹这一切
I wish you could see what I'm seeing, people.
多希望你们能够身临其境!
I wish you could be here with me!
噢 宝贝
Oh, baby!
快来吧
Bring it on!
各位听众 千万要记住
Always remember folks:
是查理最先告诉你们的!
You heard it first from Charlie!
爹地 它跟过来了
Daddy, it's following us!
别往后看 蹲下宝贝
Don't look at it. Get down on the ground, baby.
蹲下 然后抓好 别往后看
Get down on the ground and hold on. Don't look back.
别往后看 看我 看着我
Don't look back. Just look at me. Look at me.
- 你看我害怕了吗? - 嗯
- Do I look scared? - Uhum.
抓住了 宝贝 抓住
Hold on baby. Hold on tight.
爹地 我们着火了
Daddy, we're on fire!
他们在那里
There they are!
是他们 他们回来了!
It's them. It's them. It's them!
妈咪!
Mommy!
该死
Shit.
- 不 爹地 - 抓住 宝贝 抓住!
- No Dady. - Hang on baby. Hang on
- 莉莉 拉着我的手 - 快点 诺亚
- Lil, grab my hand. - Come on, Noah.
莉莉 你没事吧?
Lilly, you okay?
罗斯韦尔和玛丽莲・梦露 地图 地图!
Roswell and Marilyn Monroe, maps, maps.
- 都上来了吗? - 杰克逊!
- Everybody on? Ready? - Jackson!
他在哪儿? 他在干嘛?
Where is he? What's he doing?
- 爹地 - 不要
- Daddy! - No!
凯特 我们必须走了
Kate. We have to go.
不 我们哪儿也不去!
No, we're not going anywhere!
孩子们 系好安全带 我们要起飞了
Kids, buckle up. We're leaving.
他是我爸爸 我们得等他!
He's my dad. We're gonna wait!
不
No!
爹地
Daddy!
等等 戈登 我看见他了
Wait! Wait. Gordon, I see something.
是爹地
It's Daddy!
减速
Slow down!
杰克逊 快点!
Jackson, come on!
杰克逊 抓住我的手
Jackson. Reach for my hand!
快点!
Grab!
快到跑道尽头了
We're running out of runway.
凯特 快拉他上来
For God's sakes, Kate, pull him up.
杰克逊 抓住我的手
Jackson. Reach for my hand!
行了 我们起飞
Right. Here we go!
快点 再快点
Come on! Faster. Faster.
坐好了
Hang on
- 再快点! - 我在尽力!
- Go faster! - I'm trying!
好了 我们安全了 安全了
Okay. We're good. We're good.
那么 地图拿到了 我们现在要去哪儿?
So. Now that you got your map, where are we going?
中国
我们得找架大飞机
We're gonna need a bigger plane.
妈妈 你刚才说了 你说过了
You know you just said that, Mom. You just said that.
你不记得你刚说过吗?
You don't remember that you just said that?
没事 没事
That's okay. That's okay.
妈妈 下周我再给你打电话 还是这个时间
Listen, Mom. I'll call you next week, same time.
好吗? 注意身体 好好照顾自己
Okay? Take care now. Take care of yourself.
长官 我想你有必要看看这个
Sir. I think you need to see this.
长官 我以为他们给你多留了一张票
I thought they'd give you an extra ticket, Sir.
是给了
They did.
可我妈妈已经89岁高龄 还坐着轮椅
But my mother is almost 89. She's in a wheelchair.
脑子也不清醒
And she is easily confused.
但我确信 她想以自己的方式去见创造她的上帝
And I am confident that she'll want to meet her maker on her own terms.
- 明白吗? - 是 长官
- Okay? - Yes, sir.
- 那你带谁走? - 谁也不带!
- Who are you bringing? - Nobody.
我前妻跟我说 再也不想见到我
My ex-wife said she never wanted to see me again.
那就别见
So be it.
我们要带有用的人
We could bring people that contribute.
南美洲已被一系列大地震所摧毁
South Africa continent has been damaged by a series of major earthquakes.
死亡人数超过200万
The death toll is expected to be well over 2 million people.
里约热内卢的景象更是惨不忍睹
The devastation in Rio de Janeiro is beyond imagination.
两次8.5级地震使人们涌上街头疯抢食物
Two 8.5 tremors have left the people in the street fighting for resources.
一小时前我们收到巴西新闻台的画面
In the last hour we received this video from Globo News, Brazil.
怎么了? 天啊!
基督像倒塌了!
恐惧和骚乱弥漫全球
Fear and chaos have spread throughout the globe.
在伦敦 第30届奥运会已经停止
As in London, where the 30th Olympic Games has been suspended.
成千上万的群众朝唐宁街方向示威游行
Hundreds of thousands are marching towards 10 Downing Street
要求首相解除信息封锁
demanding a lift of the information blackout proposed by the Prime Minister.
上千个电话打进来 我们不得不关闭电话系统
Thousands of calls to the switchboard. We had to shut it down.
我们接到全球各地的报告
We're receiving reports from all across the globe.
无数恐慌的民众聚集在各地的公共场所
Millions of distraught masses are gathering in public places everywhere,
绝望的向上天祈祷
converging in desperate prayer.
各种宗教的传教士走上美国的大街小巷
Preachers of many faiths have taken their message of
宣称世界即将灭亡
the end of the world to the streets all over the U.S.
忏悔吧 时间不多了
Repent. There is still time.
那些举标志牌的人
Kind of gaulling when you realize the nutbags
原来一直是对的 真讽刺啊
with the cardboard signs had it right the whole time.
说到外面的民众 长官
All these people out there, sir.
我们现在还不发布警告吗?
Shouldn't we be issuing warnings now?
只能等登船程序结束后再说
Only when the boarding process is complete.
这是计划
That's the plan.
2010年加拿大峰会定的 记得吗?
British Columbia 2010, remember?
长官? 长官 那些计划是两年前制定的
Sir? Sir, those plans were drawn up 2 years ago.
好 大家先出去 快点 先出去
Okay, everybody out. Come on, get out.
峰会不是也确定了人类有权
Wasn't it also decided that people have the right to
为了生存而斗争吗?
fight for their lives, best way they can?
那也得等所有人上船了再说 艾德里安
After we get everyone on board, Adrian.
我认为这是错误的
I think that's wrong.
告诉人们他们死定了?
Want to tell everyone they're doomed?
会引发暴乱的
There'd be anarchy.
- 你想让总统被困在这里吗? - 继续说
- You want to jeopardize the departure of the president? - Come on
我们的使命是确保人类的延续
Our mission is to assure the continuity of our species.
我的疑问是 我能指望你吗?
My question: Can I count on you?
能吗?
Can I?
什么事?
What?
黄石公园火山爆发了 长官
The Yellowstone Caldera has erupted, sir.
火山灰将在7小时后到达华盛顿
The ash cloud will reach Washington in 7 hours.
我们得赶快让总统上飞机
We've to get the president on board.
总统在哪儿 萨莉?
Where is the president, Sally?
他说想一个人静一静
Said he wanted to spend some time alone.
- 我觉得他在小教堂里 - 他现在还去教堂?
- I think he's at the chapel. - He's going to church now?
他正在祷告 长官 现在除了祈祷还能干什么
He's praying, sir. Which is not such a bad idea.
总统先生 请您立刻上空军一号
Mr. President. I need to get you on Air Force One immediately.
让我和艾德里安单独待一会
Give me a moment with Adrian.
不是冒犯 但我们确实没时间了
No disrespect sir, we do not have time.
挤出时间
Make time.
你见过我太太桃乐西吗?
Did you ever meet my wife: Dorothy?
没有 总统先生 我没有这福气
No, sir, I never had that honor.
她去世前一会清醒 一会昏迷
She was in and out towards the end.
就在她去世前 她拉着我的手说
The night before she passed on, she took my hand and told me:
"我觉得你该去抽奖"
"I think you should have a lottery"
"每个人都该有中奖的机会"
"Everyone should have a chance to go"
也许我们早该这么做
Maybe that's what we should have done.
我将是美利坚合众国的最后一位总统
I'll be the last president of the United States of America.
你知道这是什么感觉吗 孩子?
Do you know how that feels, son?
没人能够拯救美国 总统先生
No one could have saved the country, sir.
但我想 人民有权知道真相
And I think, I think people have a right to know.
别担心 我会处理的
Don't worry, I'll take care of that.
你快走吧
Go on now.
我不会丢下您的 总统先生
Not without you, sir.
快上飞机吧 孩子
Get on that plane, son.
你要去的是个崭新的世界
It's a brave new world you head into.
一个年轻的科学家抵得上20个老政客
And a young scientist will be worth 20 old politicians.
米卡兰国际机场
拉斯维加斯
我们应该去落基山接我父母
We should go to my parents house in the Rockies.
这不会是你要写的疯狂故事吧 杰克逊?
This isn't one of your crazy stories, now. Right, Jackson?
我们怎么去得了中国?
How the hell are we going to make it to China?
嘿 戈登
Hey, Gordon.
没有杰克逊 我们连加州都逃不出来
Without Jackson we wouldn't have made it out of California.
诺亚 别插嘴
Noah, please.
小心 别弄坏起落架
Be careful with the landing gear!
别紧张 我知道自己在做什么
Easy gringo, I know what I'm doing.
大家注意 国民警卫队刚刚通知我们
Attention! The National Guard has informed us that
一团极度危险的火山灰 正往拉斯维加斯飘来
an extremely hazardous ash cloud is headed for the city of Las Vegas.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
请全体人员进入室内
快走 你不能待在这里
Move! You can't stay here.
- 我的飞机在这里 - 这里不安全
- I have a plane here. - It's not safe.
这消息你确认过了吗?
So you got positive confirmation on this?
谢谢你 我了解了
Thank you, I understand.
总统先生不来了
The President is not coming.
听着 船长不愿舍弃他下沉的的船
So, the Captain doesn't want to abandon his sinking ship.
那是他的抉择 高尚的抉择
That's his choice, and a noble one.
我也刚收到消息 副总统的直升机
I have also just learned that the Vice President's chopper
在匹兹堡外的火山灰中坠毁了
went down in the ash cloud outside Pittsburgh.
幸运的是 我们还有宪法可循
Fortunately, we have protocols to follow.
那众议院议长呢?
What about the Speaker of the House?
这么混乱 我哪知道他在哪儿?
In this chaos, I have no idea. Where is he?
现在他应该是总指挥 长官
He's the Commander in Chief now, sir.
谁让他迟到了 这趟飞机不等人的
I don't know what to tell you. This is one flight he shouldn't be late for.
告诉机长 准备起飞
Tell the Captain we're taking off.
长官 你没有这个权力
Sir, you don't have the authority.
谁有这个权利? 你吗?
Who got the authority? You? You got the authority?
你连自己的嘴都管不住
You couldn't even keep your damn mouth shut.
去年你泄露了最高机密 差点把我们全害死
You betrayed top secret information.
你在胡说什么?
What the hell are you talking about?
你把一切都告诉了你父亲 使整个计划处于危险之中
You told your father everything, put this entire plan in jeopardy.
幸好你父亲的嘴闭得比你紧
Good thing for you, the old man could keep his mouth shut better than you.
拜托 别这么吃惊
Oh, come on. Don't look so shocked.
我们必须监控所有人
We had to monitor everybody who knew.
不然怎么能把秘密保守到今天?
How do you think we kept it a secret for so long?
所以你就杀了所有想说出真相的人?
So you just killed anybody who tried to talk?
泄密的人不仅是国家的敌人
Anybody who tried to talk was not just an enemy of the state.
更是人类的公敌
They were an enemy of humanity.
卢浮宫博物馆馆长是人类公敌?
The director of the Louvre was an enemy of humanity?
他决定召开记者招待会 他就是
After he called a press conference, he was.
天啊 你想怎样呢?
Jesus, what did you think?
所有人通通都上船 手拉手唱赞歌?
We're all just gonna get on board, hold hands and sing Kumbaya?
给我坐下 系好安全带
Sit down and buckle up.
对不起 我父亲在指挥中心吗?
Excuse me, is my father in the Command Center?
总统先生刚打电话过来 威尔逊博士
President is on the line, Dr. Wilson.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
如果我告诉你 你就不会上飞机了
You never would've gotten on that plane if I told you.
- 但你说过你会和我一起的 - 我的孩子 听我说
- But you said that you'd be here. - Darling, listen to me.
知道你可以活着
Do you understand how much strength it gives me
就是给我的最大鼓励
knowing that you will survive?
我现在唯一要做的事
The only thing left to do now,
就是告诉人民真相
is tell the truth to people.
至少他们知道后
At least if they know,
家人间还可以彼此告别
families can say goodbye to each other.
母亲能安慰她的孩子
A mother can comfort her children.
而父亲
And a father...
可以请求女儿原谅自己
can ask his daughter for forgiveness.
您准备好了就开始 总统先生
Whenever you're ready, Mr President.
美国同胞们
My fellow Americans,
这是我最后一次发表讲话
this will be the last time I address you.
正如大家知道的 灾难席卷了美国
As you know, catastrophe has struck our nation,
也将席卷整个世界
has struck the world.
真希望我可以告诉你们
I wish I could tell you
我们有能力抵御这场灾难
we could prevent the coming destruction.
但我们无能为力
We cannot.
今天 没有人是陌生人
Today, none of us are strangers.
今天 我们都是一家人
Today, we are one family,
一起走进黑暗
stepping into the darkness together.
我们可能信仰不同
We are a nation of many religions,
但我相信这句话 可以代表我们共同的信仰
but I believe these words reflect the spirit of all our faiths:
耶和华是我的牧者 我必...
"The lord is my Shepard. I shall... "
出自《圣经.诗篇23篇》
大家不要靠近门和窗户
People! Get away from the doors and windows.
我们怎么办? 你告诉我
What are we gonna do? You tell me.
- 西尔伯曼医生? - 塔玛拉!
- Dr. Silberman? - Tamara!
你怎么会在这?
What are you doing here?
她是我的病人 亲爱的
She's a patient, Honey.
不好意思 我的私人飞机停在外面
Excuse me, I have a private plane out there.
卡尔波夫! 尤里!
Karpov! Yuri!
你知道真相 你一直都知道
You knew. This whole time you knew.
你有办法离开 对吧? 你有飞机
You've got a way out of here, right? You got a plane?
带我的家人一起走 求你了!
My family, take us with you. Please!
老板 老板
Boss, boss.
我找到了一架飞机 一架安东诺夫
I found us a plane. An Antonov.
他们刚才要起飞 但控制塔不准他们起飞
They were just about to take off, but the tower didn't let them.
你会飞那家伙吗?
Can you still fly that thing?
- 没问题 老板 不过我需要一个副驾驶 - 完了
- Sure, Boss, but I need co-pilot. - No.
戈登是飞行员
Gordon's a pilot.
不 我不是 我不是
No, I'm not. I'm not.
他就是 很棒的飞行员 快走吧
Yes he is. Great pilot. Let's go.
太好了 我们走!
Good. Let's go!
杰克逊 别再说我是飞行员了
Jackson, stop saying I'm a pilot.
你们不能出去 回来!
You can't go out there. Come back!
后退 大家快后退!
Move back, people!
哇 真是架大飞机
Wow, that's a big plane.
俄罗斯造的
It's Russian.
大家快上去 快点!
Let's move everybody. Come on!
- 戈登 你在哪儿? - 我来了!
- Gordon, where are you? - Let's go!
快上来 戈登 快点!
Up here, Gordon. Hurry up!
我的上帝 又来了
Oh my God. Not again.
拉斯维加斯车展
- 哇哦 好酷啊 - 拉斯维加斯车展
- Woah, look at these. - Las Vegas auto show.
我们还有贵宾卡
We had VIP tickets for this.
太好了 我们走吧
That's fantastic, let's go.
检查液压系统 我来平衡油箱
Check the main bus for hydraulics, I'll balance the tanks.
什么?
What?
好的 我尽力 我尽力试试
Okay, okay. I'm trying. Okay? I'm trying.
控制塔呼叫安东诺夫 你们到底在干什么?
Tower to Antonov, what the hell are you doing?
立刻停下来
Shut down immediately.
凯撒 乖
Caesar, shh.
我一说"走" 就把它推到底 明白吗?
When I say "go", we push all this down at once, okay?
- 明白 - 走!
- Okay. - Go!
安东诺夫 停止起飞 你没有起飞许可
Antonov, abort take-off. You do not have clearance.
重复 停止起飞!
I repeat, you must abort.
刚怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
不知道 但听起来不妙
I don't know, but it's not good.
- 推! - 正在推!
- Push! - Pushing!
要掉下去了! 要掉下去了!
We're going down! We're going down!
- 什么? - 肯定是泵出问题了! 你接手!
- What? - It must be the pump. Take over.
接手? 什么我接手?
Take over? What do you mean take over?
- 萨沙! - 别紧张
- Sasha! - Relax.
上帝! 我的上帝啊!
God! God! Jesus!
- 哦上帝! - 我搞定了
- Oh God! - I think I got it
- 萨沙 快来! - 深呼吸
- Sasha, now! - Take a deep breath.
拉!
Pull!
宝贝 快把屁股抬起来
那是埃菲尔铁塔?
Was that the Eiffel Tower?
大概是吧
I think so.
女士们先生们 我们正飞往中国
Ladies and Gentlemen. We're on our way to China.
好 非常好
Good. Very good.
不要相信那些传闻 尼玛
师傅 可丹增是我哥哥
他在造大船的隧道里工作
如果丹增说得没错 世界末日真的来了
以仁波切的智慧 您会怎么做?
仁波切是对西藏佛法成就者的尊称
已经满了 仁波切
别再倒了
就像这个杯子 你的内心被恐惧与猜疑所填满
想要看到智慧之光 你先要平静你的内心
注意离合器
不好挂档
奶奶
他爷爷 尼玛来了
奶奶 丹增让我带个消息
他叫我们去卓铭谷的工地找他
他说有办法带我们上船
你在说什么呢?
丹增不是在建大坝吗?
奶奶
其实他们在建大船 政府骗了我们
洪水就要来了
我们必须马上走
尼玛 谁借给你的车?
有一次我们坐船 你爷爷吐了一路
还是先吃饭吧
- 瞧 新款宾利 - 我爸爸订过一辆
- Hey, look, the new Bentley! - Our father had one on order.
本来明年就能拿到
He was supposed to get it next year.
但因为要坐大船 他又取消了
But then he canceled it. Because of the ships.
你们家有几辆车?
How many cars does your family have?
我妈的男朋友有辆保时捷
My mom's boyfriend has a Porsche.
我们的爸妈也离婚了
Our parents are divorced too.
是啊 我们对此也无能为力
Yeah, but there is nothing that we can do about that.
找到帽子了
Found a hat.
她很喜欢帽子
She has a thing for hats.
我在她这么大的时候也一样
I was just like that at her age.
帽子让我感到安全
They made me feel safe.
那么 你是怎么认识西尔伯曼医生的?
So, how did you meet Dr. Silberman?
很明显 和你认识他的方式不同
As you can see, not the same way you did.
我男朋友让我去隆胸
My boyfriend asked me to get them done.
他不是你丈夫?
He's not your husband?
不 我们没结婚 估计以后也不可能结婚
We are not married. And probably never will be.
给你孩子的
For the boys.
她们相处的不错
They seem to like each other.
是啊
Yeah, I guess.
说真的 卡尔波夫先生 你付了多少钱?
Tell me, Mr. Karpov, how much did you pay?
一个座位10亿欧元
One billion Euro. Per seat.
- 真夸张 - 是吗?
- That's disgusting. - Oh yeah?
你知道的 柯蒂斯 我以前不是生意人
You know, Curtis, I wasn't always a businessman.
我是个拳击手
I am a boxer.
我年轻时在摩尔曼斯克打拳
Was my only playing when I was boy back in Murmansk.
我的教练也叫尤里 他常常跟我说
And my coach, his name was also Yuri. He always said:
"如果有人想击倒你 那他必须先杀了你"
"If someone wants to beat you he has to kill you first."
说得好
That's very nice.
告诉我 如果你和我一样有钱 你会像我这样做吗?
But tell me, what would you have done if you were rich like me?
看 他们都是很棒的孩子
Look, they are wonderful children.
各位注意 我们计划在夏威夷加油
OK, guys. The plan is to refill in Hawaii,
请坐好并系上安全带
so sit down and buckle up.
剩下的交给我和戈登
Gordon and I will do the rest.
噢 上帝啊
Oh God.
叫他们过来
Go get the guys.
伙计们 有点问题... 你们也许该...
Guys, there's a... You might wanna...
- 这是哪儿? - 夏威夷
- What is that? - The state of Hawaii
不好 非常不好
Not good. That is not good.
- 我们还有多少油? - 不够了
- How much fuel do we have left? - Not enough.
我们得在中国南海附近迫降
We have to make a water landing somewhere in South China sea.
好极了 至少不用起落架
Great, at least we won't need a landing gear.
- 起落架怎么了? - 都落在拉斯维加斯了
- What about it? - We lost it all, in Vegas.
威尔逊博士 我可以进来吗?
Dr. Wilson, may I come in?
不好意思 恐怕我的心情不太好
I'm not a very good company, I'm afraid.
- 博士 - 叫我艾德里安就好
- Doctor... - Please, call me Adrian.
对于所有不能上船的人
All those people we left behind.
他们都没有机会了 对吗?
They don't stand a chance, do they?
我相信大自然会作出选择的
I believe that nature will choose for itself,
从它自身来决定谁该继续生存
from itself, what will survive.
就像你一样 保护那些伟大的艺术品
Just like you, preserving those great artworks.
人类的文化就是我们的灵魂 今晚它不会灭亡
Our culture is our soul, and that's not dying tonight.
拜托 我帮你们掩人耳目?
Come on, I contributed to this cover up?
达・芬奇 毕加索 这些艺术品都上船了
The Da Vinci, Picasso, they're in.
但如果你是无名小卒 你就没有机会
But if you're some nobody you don't stand a chance.
这不一定完全正确
It's not necessarily true.
你听过一个叫杰克逊・柯蒂斯的作家吗?
Did you ever hear of a writer called Jackson Curtis?
他写了一本书 《再见亚特兰蒂斯》
Wrote a book, "Farewell Atlantis".
他的这本书只卖出了500本
What do you think the chances are of an unknown writer
你觉得他的书能留存下来的概率是多少?
who barely sold 500 copies making it aboard this plane?
我不明白
I don't understand.
无论这是机会或者信念或者命运 这些都不重要
I mean call it chance or faith or nature, doesn't matter.
这本书已经是我们的遗产了 为什么?
This book is part of our legacy now. Why?
因为我正在读它
Because I'm reading it.
赫尔姆斯利博士 请马上到指挥中心
Dr. Helmsley, please report to the situation room.
喂 你是谁?
你好 打扰了
Hello, I'm sorry.
- 请问你是哪位? - 我是洋子・德尔加多
- Who is this? - This is Yoko Delgado.
你找我爹地吗?
Do you want to speak to my daddy?
是的 麻烦你了
Yes, please.
我要说是谁打来的呢?
Who should I say is calling?
- 就说是他爸爸 - 你是我的爷爷?
- Tell him, its his father. - You're my grandpa?
是的 宝贝 我是你爷爷
Yes, sweetheart, I am.
爹地 爹地 爷爷来电话了
Daddy, Daddy, grandpa is on the phone.
总统先生
Mr President, Sir.
- 怎么了 宝贝? - 她找不到她爸爸了
- What's the matter, sweety? - She can't find her daddy.
你们为什么不坐到沙发上去 那里舒服些 莎莉
Why don't you two get comfy on that couch? Sally.
过来帮帮她们
Come here and help them.
我去找你爸爸
I'll find your daddy.
谁负责登记失踪人员?
Who can help me with missing persons?
抱歉 老兄 我现在真的忙不过来
Sorry, man, I'm really busy right now.
我是说没问题 不好意思 总统先生
I mean of course, sir. Sorry, Mr President.
没关系 孩子 你干得很好
Don't worry about it, you're doing a great job, son.
- 怎么了? - 首都发生了9.4级地震
- What's happening? - The Capitol has been hit by a 9.4
我们和白宫失去了联系 长官
Lost communication with the White House, sir.
- 震中在哪里? - 北切萨皮克湾
- Where is it centered? - North Chesapeake Bay.
安海斯先生 俄罗斯总统打来电话
Mr. Anheuser, Russian president on the line, sir.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我们刚刚进入中国领空
We just entered Chinese air space.
这是肯定的 总统先生
That's affirmative, Mr. President.
在恢复通讯之前 由我暂任总指挥
Until communication is restored, I suppose I am in command.
其他国家的元首也都在去中国的途中
It appears that all other heads of state are enroute,
除了意大利总理
with the exception of the Italian Prime Minister,
他也决定留下来向上天祈祷
Who has also decided to stay behind and trust in prayer.
地壳开始移动了 赫尔姆斯利博士
Earth's crust has begun to shift, Dr. Helmsley!
- 移动了多少? - 1.2度 还在移动
- By what degree? - 1.2 degree. Still moving.
那接下来会怎么样?
So, what happens next?
大陆位移结束之后
The movement of our land masses comes to a halt.
让我们看看仿真图
Let's see a simulation.
会形成巨大的海啸
Expect the formation of gigantic tsunamis.
和地震强度成正比
Proportional to the magnitude of corresponding quakes.
- 放大日本海的图像 - 是 长官
- Pull up the Japanese sea border. - Yes, sir.
我爸爸在那附近的一条游轮上
My dad's on a cruise ship out there.
不过我猜你早就知道了
But I guess you already knew that.
长官 我们监测到了两次深海地震 分别是7.9级和8.2级
Sir, we've recorded two underwater quakes at 7.9 and 8.2.
根据最新消息
From what we have just learned,
东京发生了极其强烈的地震
Tokyo seems to have taken the full force of the earthquake.
有消息称
At this point unconfirmed reports indicate that
日本大片陆地已沉入海底
large areas of land are under water.
托尼
Tony.
我打电话了
I called.
但已经晚了
I was too late.
可能他们逃出去了
Maybe they got out of town.
谁也说不准
You never know...
哈里!
Harry!
我来了 桃乐西
I'm coming home, Dorothy.
有信号吗?
Anything?
什么都没有
Nothing but static.
连紧急信号都没有
Not even an emergency signal.
不敢想像地面上发生了什么
Can't think about what's going on down there.
还记得我们以前露营时开的旧甲壳虫吗?
Remember that old Beetle we used to camp in?
你从来没把顶棚打开过
But you'd never get the roof up.
我们真该换辆车
We definitely traded up.
带孩子出去玩时
Tried to find our old spot at Yellowstone.
本想去黄石公园找我们的老地方 但是
When I went camping with the kids, but...
我找不到了
I couldn't find it.
你觉得人会变吗?
Do you think people change?
你指的是我吗?
By people, do you mean me?
对
Yes.
我们分手后 你觉得你变了吗?
Do you think you've changed since we separated?
我也经常吃麦片粥了
I seem to eat a lot more cereal now.
你以前总是埋头写书
You always had tunnel vision.
其他的什么你都不管
You could just block everything out and write.
也不管我们
You blocked us out.
你爱他吗?
Do you love him?
我很爱他
I love him enough.
全球的地面通讯都中断了 长官
All global ground communication is ceased, sir.
卫星只能接收到卓铭谷的信号
The only signals our satellites are picking up come from Cho Ming.
这算是个好消息
Well there's a piece of good news.
有新情况吗 博士?
Any updates, Doctor?
海啸将袭击各大洲
We expect the tsunamis to reach land fall on every continent.
卓铭谷也会在6小时后遭到海啸袭击
The Cho Ming area will be impacted in approximately 6 hours.
地壳已经向西南方向移动了23度
It looks like the crust have shifted by almost 23 degrees to the southwest.
数据显示
The data also shows
地球两极的磁场分布也颠倒了
the Earth's poles have reversed their magnetic fields.
这是它们的新位置
These are their new positions.
你的意思是 现在的北极
You're telling me that the North Pole
跑到威斯康辛州附近了?
is now somewhere in Wisconsin?
事实上 现在那里是南极
Actually, thats the South Pole now.
快撑不住了
出什么事了?
引擎熄火 6个废了2个
Engine failure. 2 of 6 are down.
你们必须做好准备
You must get ready.
- 还能撑多久? - 15分钟 运气好的话
- How long do we have? - 15 minutes. Maybe.
最好叫醒孩子们
Better wake up the kids.
你为什么讨厌戈登?
Why do you hate Gordon?
嘿 拜托
Hey. Come on.
你在说什么啊? 我不讨厌他
What are you talking about? I don't hate him.
反正你不喜欢他
You don't like him either
也许是因为我不了解他
That's because I don't know him well, maybe.
但我了解
But I do.
一旦你了解他 就会知道他真的很好
He's really nice once you get to know him.
你该多和他聊聊
You should talk to him more often.
你们会相处得很好的
You guys would get along really well.
你真的很喜欢他 对吧?
You like him a lot, huh?
我会尽力的 我保证 好吗?
I'll do my best. I promise. OK?
我真的为你感到骄傲
I'm really proud of you. Really proud of you.
快到了吗?
Is it time?
是的
Yeah
- 快准备好 - 穿救生衣 亚力克
爹地 怎么了?
Dad, what's wrong?
萨沙说要降落了 会有点颠簸
Sasha's gotta land. It's gonna be a little bumpy.
可能还会有点滑
Maybe a little wet.
爹地?
Daddy?
按住了
Hold her steady.
爹地 我真的不太会游泳
Daddy, I'm not a really good swimmer.
嘿 没关系 有救生衣呢
Hey, that's alright. It's what you got this for.
就像在家里的游泳池
It's like being in a swimming pool.
只是装备更酷 有哨子 还有灯
Only it's got more cool stuff. It's got a whistle, a light.
我以为我们要去中国
I thought we were going to China.
不 我们要在这里降落
No, we gotta land here.
这就是我们要做的
So that's what we're gonna do.
我们要呆在一起 对吧?
We're just gonna all stay together. Right?
不 我们都会死
No we're not, we're gonna die!
不 我们不会死
No, we're not.
保证吗?
Promise?
我向你们保证 不管发生什么 我们都会在一起
I promise you, we'll all stay together, no matter what happens.
杰克逊 尤里
Jackson, Yuri.
我想你们最好上来看看
I think you better come up here
等等 我去看看就回来
Hold on, I'm gonna go check this out.
- 爹地 爹地 - 我马上回来
- Dad, Dad! - I'll be right back
好了 嘿 系好安全带 快点
OK, hey, hey. We gotta buckle up. Let's go.
别问我怎么回事
Don't ask me how that happened.
我们现在不在海上
There is no more ocean,
而且我们就要到目的地了
and we're pretty close to where we wanted to go.
看来整个世界好像移动了1000英里
It's like the whole world shifted by 1000 miles.
准确的说是 1578英里
1578 to be exact.
这叫做"地壳漂移理论"
It's called "Earth Crust Displacement Theory"
哈普古德教授在1958年提出的
Professor Hapgood 1958.
真有你的 查理
Way to go, Charlie.
怎么了?
What was that?
最后两个引擎也熄火了
We just lost our last two engines.
我要在下面紧急降落
I'll shoot for that glacier.
会很颠簸
It's going to get rocky.
听好 这有些疯狂
Listen, it's gonna sound crazy,
但现在也只能这样做了
but here's what you have to do.
都起来! 跟我来!
Get up! Follow me!
尤里 我们要怎么做?
Yuri, what are you doing?
我们要开宾特利了
We are taking the Bentley!
等等! 还没到时候
Not yet! Not yet.
再等会儿
Almost there.
快上车!
Get in the car.
好了 开舱门! 快拉!
Okay, go now! Pull!
快走 杰克逊
Go, Jackson.
我们要等萨沙和戈登
We gotta wait for Sasha and Gordon.
快走! 确保所有人在着陆前都下飞机
Go! Make sure everybody gets off the plane before I touch down.
那你呢?
What about you?
不用管我 我要保证飞机降落
I'll be fine. I have to touch this plane down.
你还等什么? 快走! 快!
What are you waiting for? Go!
我看到他了 他来了
There he is. I see him!
- 萨沙呢? - 快点 我们走
- Where is Sasha? - Come on let's go.
- 萨沙在哪儿? - 他说他会没事的
- Where is Sasha? - He said he's fine
在飞机着陆前我们要出去
We should get out of here before he touches down.
不 不 不 我们得等他!
No, no, no. Don't go! We should wait for him.
杰克逊 快走
Go Jackson, go.
没法启动
It won't start.
通通闭嘴!
Shut up everybody!
引擎
Engine.
启动
Start.
声控的 很帅吧?
Voice control. Sold me on it.
下面 降落
欢迎来到中华人民共合国
Welcome, to the People's Republic of China.
很高兴能来 打招呼 孩子们
Good to be here. Say hi, kids.
- 你们的通行证是什么颜色? - 什么?
- What color are your passes? - What?
你们的登船通行证是什么颜色?
What color are your boarding passes?
我有绿色的
I have green cards.
- 上面有我和我儿子的名字 - 什么?
- For my boys and me. - What?
尤里? 尤里!
Yuri? Yuri!
尤里 没搞错吧 你在开玩笑对吗?
Yuri. It's a mistake. A joke, right?
怎么? 你以为我不知道你和萨沙的事?
What? You think I didn't know about you and Sasha?
愿上帝保佑那个混蛋的灵魂吧
May God bless that poor bastard's soul.
各位 抱歉了 祝你们好运
I'm sorry guys. Good luck.
走吧 孩子们
Come on, boys.
- 也许我们可以用钱贿赂他们 - 我有钱
- Maybe with money we could bribe them. - I do, I do.
你有10亿欧元吗?
You got a billion Euros?
威尔逊博士 我是迈克尔斯上校 美国方舟的船长
Dr. Wilson. I'm Captain Michaels, Skipper of the American ship.
请接受我对您父亲最诚挚的哀悼
Please accept my sincere condolences for your father.
谢谢你 船长
Thank you, Captain.
安海斯先生 你们是最后到的
Mr. Anheuser. Your party is the last to arrive.
船长 我们收到报告说方舟损坏严重
There's been reports of severe damage, Captain.
3号方舟的情况如何?
What's the status of Ark number 3?
全面评估尚未结束
We haven't done a complete assessment yet.
不过情况不容乐观
Looks like we lost it.
牙刷都不带 只带书
No toothbrush. Only books.
小时候 我爸爸经常出差
When I was a kid my dad was on the road a lot.
他总是给我留一箱书
He'd always leave me a box full of books.
每晚打电话监督我
Call me and cruise me.
每读完一本 我就可以得到一个冰淇淋蛋卷
I'd get an ice cream cone for every book I read so...
所以我小时候很胖
I was a fat kid.
真不敢相信
I find that very hard to believe.
是真的 我高中就读完了两千本书
No, its true, my high school carrier was 2000 books
一个女朋友没有
Zero girlfriends.
我上大学前甚至都没亲过男孩子
I didn't even kiss a boy until I was in college.
他们都很怕我爸爸
They were all too scared of my dad.
把这个项目交给中国是正确的
Leave it to the Chinese.
换作其他国家
I didn't think it was possible.
肯定无法完成
Not in the time we had.
那就是3号方舟 长官
That's Ark number 3, sir.
地壳移动时 顶棚坍塌了
The roof collapsed during the shifting of the Earth's crust.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
由于技术问题 3号方舟登船程序推迟
Boarding of Arc 3 will be delayed due to technical difficulties.
嘿 到底怎么了?
Hey, what's going on here?
我和我的儿子都有绿卡
I have a green card for my boys and me.
我要和你们的主管谈
I want to speak to your supervisor.
我就是主管
I am the supervisor.
回去跟其他拿绿卡的人一起排队 否则就拘留你
Get back with the other green cards, or I'll have you detained.
他说你和萨沙的事 是真的吗?
What he said about you and Sasha, is it true?
萨沙比尤里强100倍
Sasha was worth a hundred times a man like Yuri.
我早该听你的 西尔伯曼医生
I should have listened to you, Dr. Silberman.
其实我很喜欢我之前的样子 都是那个混蛋叫我去整形
I actually liked the way I looked before that monster talked me into it.
他还叫我打折呢
Did you know he asked me for a discount?
而且是分期付款
He payed in installments.
吝啬的混蛋
Cheap bastard.
听到了吗?
You hear that?
在那里!
Over there!
停车!
Stop!
停车! 停车!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
停车 停车
直升机马上就要降落机坪 请做好准备
这些人是怎么选出来的?
How were all these people chosen?
跟你的艺术品一样
Same way your Arc was.
由世界各地遗传专家来决定
By experts from all over the world.
我们需要需要保留下来的优秀基因
We had geneticists determine the perfect gene pool we need to repopulate.
这些人也是靠基因选出来的?
These people were chosen by geneticists?
所有的绿卡持有者 请到D4站台
All green card holders, please proceed to hangar D-4.
看来是支票让他们登船的
Looks to me like their check books got them on board.
说的没错 威尔逊博士
That's right, Dr. Wilson.
没有私人巨额资金的支持
Without billions of dollars from the private sector
就没有这整个项目
this entire operation would've been impossible.
我们竟然还卖票?
We sold tickets?
那这些工人呢?
What about all these workers?
他们能上船吗?
They all get passes?
想说什么? 人生不公平? 这就是你想说的?
What? Life isn't fair? Is that it?
要是你想让这些中国工人上船
If you want to donate your passes to a couple of Chinese workers,
你尽可以捐出你的通行证
you be my guest.
船长 我要一个出发前的简报
Captain, I want a pre-launch briefing.
每个国家都要有
All international teams present.
搞什么鬼?
What the hell?
搞什么? 这里可以挤10个人!
What is this? They could've fit 10 people in here.
萨特南来电
萨特南 你在哪儿?
Satnam, where are you?
- 在南畔高原 - 什么?
- On the Nampan Plateau. - What?
海啸正在从东面过来
There's a tidal wave coming from the east.
巨大无比
It's gigantic.
萨特南 出什么事了?
Satnam, what happened?
没人来接我们 艾德里安
We never got picked up, Adrian.
飞机根本没来
The airlift never came.
永别了 我的朋友
Goodbye, my friend.
萨特南
Satnam
- 玛丽 我们的设备在哪儿? - 在那边
- Mary, Mary, where are we set up? - Over there.
- 给我印度南畔高原的卫星图像 - 好的 马上
- Give me the satellite images from Napam, India. - OK, right away.
怎么了?
What's happening?
萨特南说有另一股海啸 从东面过来
Satnam was talking about another wave, coming from the east.
圣母玛利亚
Holy mother of God.
洪水会提前到来?
So the flooding will hit earlier?
你的意思是 第二股海啸就要来了?
You are telling me that the second wave is closer?
输入新的数据
Plug in the new data.
没有人去接萨特南!
Satnam didn't get picked up.
什么?
What?
现在这么乱 很多人都没法接
A lot of people didn't get picked up in this chaos.
这不是阴谋 赫尔姆斯利
This is not a conspiracy, Helmsley.
你的预测也不全都准确 对吧 博士?
Your predictions haven't exactly panned out, have they, Doctor?
准备好了
It's ready.
天啊 1500米高
Oh God, its 1500 meters high.
还有多久会到这里?
When will it get here?
告诉我 赫尔姆斯利 还有多久会到?
Talk to me, Hemsley, when will it hit?
打开倒计时
Adjust the countdown.
距离冲击时间还有28分10秒
28 minutes, 10 seconds to impact.
天啊
My God.
船长
Captain.
我要立刻和其他国家的元首谈谈
I need to speak to the other heads of state immediately.
- 马上 泰勒? - 是 船长
- Right away. Taylor? - Aye, Captain
4号方舟待命 6号方舟待命 7号方舟待命
Standing by. Ark 6, stand by. Ark 7, stand by.
我是卡尔・安海斯 4号方舟的代理指挥
This is Carl Anheuser acting CIC on 4,
是 长官
Yes sir
请求召开T-99紧急会议
Requesting emergency conference T-99.
他非常喜欢你 你知道吗?
He thinks the world of you, you know that?
他是个好孩子
He's a great little man.
是的
Yeah
我一直想拥有自己的家庭
I always wanted to have a family of my own.
你很幸运 杰克逊
You're a lucky man, Jackson.
你一定要记住
Don't ever forget it.
他们是谁?
我们在路上遇到的
送他们回去!
我是大喇嘛仁波切的弟子
你知道我不能这么做
你不用带我们所有人走
You don't have to take all of us.
只要带上我的孩子就行 求求你了
Please just take my children. I'm begging you.
我为什么要这么做?
Why should I do that?
你不也想救你的家人吗? 求你了!
Same reason you sent for your family. Please!
请带上孩子 不用管我们
Please just the children, you don't have to take us.
求你了!
Please!
求你了 上帝啊!
Please. Oh my God.
求你了 我不知道你是否听得懂
Please. I don't know if you can understand what I'm saying.
但我们都是母亲 求你了
As a mother, I'm begging you.
带上孩子吧
Please take them.
求你了
Please.
丹增 我们都是大地的子女
奶奶 人太多 计划就行不通了
带他们所有人一起走
带上他们
所有建筑工人马上撤离
所有工作人员做好准备
请所有建筑工人马上撤离
所有机组人员马上登船
他们把门打开了
They're opening the mountain.
他们要弃我们而去
They are leaving without us.
退后 你听见没有!
Get back. What did I tell you!
他们也要把你丢下了 看 傻瓜!
They are leaving you behind too. Look, idiot.
跟我来
Follow me.
我们得快点 他们要走了
启动安全程序
Initiating security procedures.
打扰下 艾德里安・赫尔姆斯利在哪儿?
Excuse me. Where can I find Adrian Helmsley?
在船上 跟我来
He's on the bridge. This way.
丹增 等等
奶奶 我们就快到了
压力正常吗 安东?
Green lights on pressure, Mr. Anton?
一切正常 船长
Green lights across the board, Captain.
为什么会有锚?
Why do they have anchors?
因为这不是太空船 是方舟
Because they're not space ships. They're Arcs.
快走吧
Let's go.
总统先生
Mr. President.
看看这个
You've got to see this.
启动加固装置
Engage the support mechanisms.
是 船长 启动加固装置
Aye-aye, Captain. Engaging supports.
这些支架大概能
Just exactly how long are these things
支持我们多久 船长?
expected to hold us in place, Captain?
它们只能抵抗第一波海啸的冲击 安海斯先生
They're just meant to withstand the first impact of the waves, Mr. Anheuser.
下去 奥列格 你先走
Down there Oleg, you go first.
凯撒
Caesar!
凯撒 非常好!
好孩子 到妈妈这来
Good, good boy. Come to Mommy.
凯撒!
Caesar!
妈咪 塔玛拉呢?
Mommy, where's Tamara?
爸爸 快看!
- 塔玛拉 - 马上就来
- Tamara! - I'm coming.
接住!
Take it!
上帝啊 外面怎么回事?
Oh my god, what's happening out there?
安海斯说服了各国元首 马上启航
Anheuser convinced the other heads of state to launch.
安霍伊泽先生
Mr. Anheuser
必须停止外面的悲剧
We have to stop this madness.
让其它船都能看到我
Make sure the other bridges can see me.
你要干什么?
What do you think you're doing?
我知道我要干什么 打开吧
I know exactly what I'm doing. Turn it on.
女士们先生们 我是艾德里安・赫尔姆斯利博士
Ladies and Gentleman, this is Dr. Adrian Helmsley
已故总统威尔逊的首席科学顾问
Chief science adviser to the late President Wilson.
把声音开大点 霍夫曼先生
Could you please turn up the volume, Mr. Hoffman.
我知道为了保存人类的文明
I know we've all been forced to make difficult decisions
我们必须做出困难的抉择
to save our human civilization.
但作为人类 就意味着要相互关心
But to be human means to care for each other
所谓文明 就是要共同去创造更美好的生活
and civilization means to work together to create a better life.
如果是这样 那我们此时的行为
If that's true, then there's nothing human
就没有一丝人性和文明可言
and nothing civilized about what we're doing here.
赫尔姆斯利博士的热情令人钦佩
Dr. Helmsley's passion is admirable,
但我不得不提醒大家
But I remind you that
我们的资源有限 而且时间紧迫
we have very limited resources and extremely limited time.
扪心自问 我们能袖手旁观 看着这些人去死吗?
Ask yourselves, can we really stand by and watch these people die?
两天前我读到一句话
I read a quote two days ago.
作者现在可能已经死了 但他说
The author is probably dead by now. But he said:
"等到我们不再为他人而战时"
"The moment we stop fighting for each other"
"我们也就失去了人性"
"That's the moment that we lose our humanity."
为了拯救人类
And in order to save the human race,
我们制定了这个计划 并遵守着
we have and obligation to stick to this plan
这里的各国元首都签字同意了
which every nation on this flotilla signed up for.
他们现在只能听天由命!
They're in God's hands now.
军官 你把它关掉
Officer, you turn that off.
这是命令 关掉!
That is an order, sailor. Turn it off!
你敢关掉试试 年轻人!
Don't you dare touch that button, young man!
你们通通都疯了吗?
Have you completely lost your mind?
看看时间
Look at the clock!
我们只有可怜的15分钟了!
We have barely 15 minutes left!
你能为人类的灭绝负责吗?
Do you want to be responsible for the extinction of the human race?
你能负责吗 艾德里安?
Can you handle that, Adrian?
有一位年轻的印度天体物理学家
There's a young astrophysicist from India
我们能在这儿都是他的功劳
who's the reason we are all here.
噢 得了吧
Oh, for God's sake.
是他发现了这一切
He's the one who discovered it all.
是他把所有线索连在一起 是他救了我们所有人
He connected all the dots, we all owe him our lives.
我刚刚得知
I just learned that
他和他的家人在印度东部发生的海啸中丧生
he was killed with his family in a Tsunami in eastern India.
他是我的好朋友
He was my friend.
他就这样白白的死了
And he died in vain.
那里的所有人都白死了
Everybody out there has died in vain.
如果我们用如此残酷的方式开创未来
If we start our future with an act of cruelty,
我们怎么向孩子交代?
what will you tell your children?
他们又怎么向下一代交代?
What will they tell theirs?
如果我父亲在这里 他不会袖手旁观
If my father were here, he would open the gates.
俄罗斯人民以及
The people of Russia along with,
中国
China
和日本
and Japan
同意
Agree
把门打开!
To open the gates!
英国 西班牙 法国 加拿大 德国
The United Kingdom, Spain, France, Canada, Germany,
我想我也可以代表意大利总理
and I believe I may also speak for the Italian Prime Minister,
我们赞成让这些人进来
We vote to let these people come in.
迈克尔斯船长
Captain Michaels.
请开门
Please
我是船长
This is your Captain.
请稍候 我们将打开大门
In a few moments, we will open the gates.
好臭啊
Phew, it stinks.
- 他们正在开门 - 快! 快!
- They are opening the gate. - Go! Go!
诺亚 快点!
Noah. Move it!
诺亚! 诺亚!
Noah! Noah!
妈妈 出事了
Mom, something happened.
坚持住!
Hold on!
戈登 抓紧 他妈的! 把手给我!
Gordon, hold on. God damn it! Give me your hand! Give me your hand!
- 把手给我! - 救我!
- Reach for it! - Help me!
拉住我的手
Reach for it!
戈登!
Gordon!
快爬上去 快爬!
门怎么了?
What's wrong with the gate?
好像是门没有完全打开 我们正在检查
Looks like it didn't run the full cycle. We're checking it out.
距离冲击还有四分钟
4 minutes to impact.
- 我们满载了 船长 - 那就关门 马上!
- We're all loaded, Captain. - Then let's lock it up. Now!
奥列格 抓住我的手
Oleg! Grab my hand!
奥列格
Oleg!
有东西卡住了液压装置 船长
Something's jamming the hydraulics, Captain.
看在上帝的份上 快把故障排除
Well then get it out for Christ sake.
门不关上我们就没法启动引擎
I can't fire up the engines until we get a good seal on that gate.
船长 有人闯入动物区
Captain, we have a breach in the zoological bay.
- 可以放大吗? - 可以
- Can you zoom in? - Yeah.
我认识那几个孩子
I know those kids.
怎么回事? 到底发生了什么?
What is happening? What's going on?
他们从哪儿进来的?
Where did they come from?
在那里 从液压舱进来的
There. Through the hydraulic chamber.
船长 找到故障原因了
Captain, I think we found the problem!
- 他们是谁? - 等等!
- Who are these people? - No, wait!
那个人受伤了
He's injured.
可能出事了
Something must've gone wrong.
可能出事了? 可能...
Something must've gone wrong? Something must've gone...
你在开玩笑吗? 当然出事了!
Are you kidding me? Of course something went wrong!
应该恭喜你们俩
You know, congratulations to the both of you.
把我们全害死也没关系
Might have gotten us all killed,
只要你问心无愧 对吧 赫尔姆斯利?
but as long as your conscience is clean, right Helmsley?
船长 派紧急救援小队下去
Captain, get an emergency team down there,
我会在液压舱和他们会合
I'll meet them at the hydraulics chamber.
- 你知道怎么走吗? - 知道
- You know your way around here? - Yeah
我们走
Let's go!
距离冲击还有一分钟
1 minute to impact.
船长?
Captain?
卓明谷机场已经被摧毁
Cho Ming airfield has been hit.
- 启动紧急通讯系统 泰勒 - 可以了 船长
- Put me on emergency comm, Mr. Taylor. - You're on it, Captain.
大家注意 我是船长
This is the Captain speaking
我们马上就会遭到洪水冲击
We expect to be impacted by water shortly.
我们得走这里
We need to go this way.
所有控制台准备接受冲击
All stations prepare for impact.
冲击压力逼近80帕
Impact pressure just climbed 80 Pascal.
表面传感器受到0.2密尔的表面压力
Surface compression of valve sensors, Captain.
我找到赫尔姆斯利博士了
I tracked Dr. Helmsley.
在那儿
There!
让开! 让一下! 让一下!
Out of the way! Excuse me. Excuse me.
丹增 快到了
尼玛 怎么了?
塔玛拉!
Tamara!
把孩子们带过去
Will you take the kids please?
怎么走?
Which way?
我们过不去 船尾进水了
We can't get there! Water is entering the stern.
船后面淹掉后 会自动开始逐舱封闭
The rear of this ship is flooded and will seal up one compartment at a time.
戈登呢?
Where's Gordon?
不
No?
我们得回去
We gotta go back!
我们必须回去
We have to go back!
妈咪
Mommy!
- 救命! - 妈咪!
- Help! - Mommy!
快爬过去 莉莉
Go over, Lilly!
凯撒! 莉莉 带上它!
Caesar! Lilly, take him!
妈咪!
Mommy!
还有别的路到液压舱吗?
Is there another way to the hydraulics chamber?
这梯子通到哪儿?
Where does this ladder go?
- 通向动物区 - 好 快走!
- To the zoological bay. - Okay, let's go!
教授 那是空军一号
Professor? It's Air Force One.
中锚被击中了
The mid-ship anchor support is hit.
可以加固吗?
Can you stabilize it?
尾锚也不行了
The bow anchor is giving in.
船长 涡轮没有反应
Captain, the turbines aren't responding.
跳过这个 手动发动引擎
So override it. Hit the override. Start the engine.
门没关好就发动不了引擎
We can't start the engine until we close that gate.
救我 救命啊!
Help me! Help!
妈妈! 妈妈!
Momma! Momma!
- 你没事吧? - 我妈咪在那里面 救救她!
- Are you OK? - My mommy is in there. Please help her!
我们会去救你妈咪的 宝贝
We'll get to your mommy, sweetheart.
我们会尽全力的 好吗?
They're doing everything they can, okay?
能和她说话吗?
Can we talk to her?
我试试看
I'm gonna try to connect us.
我们要先给他止血!
We have to stop the bleeding!
用我的皮带
How about my belt?
柯蒂斯先生? 杰克逊?
Mr. Curtis? Jackson?
救命! 嘿!
Help! Hey!
我是艾德里安・赫尔姆斯利 我们在黄石公园见过
It's Adrian Helmsley, we met at Yellowstone.
太好了 快点把这该死的门打开!
Thats great. Open the God damn door!
你女儿在我这边!
Your daughter is with me!
- 莉莉? - 诺亚在哪儿?
- Lilly? - Where's Noah?
我就在这儿 莉莉
I'm right here, Lil!
冲击警告!
Impact warning!
30度以西 45度以东
30°West, 45°East.
目标高度29035英尺(约8850米)
Target elevation 29,035 feet.
两万九千英尺? 什么意思?
29,000 feet? What the hell is at 29.000 feet?
正前方就是珠穆朗玛峰北侧 安海斯先生
We're headed straight for the north face of Mount Everest, Mr. Anheuser.
如果还不能发动引擎
And if we can't start our engines,
我们就只能等死了
we will not survive the impact.
杰克逊 舱门封住了 我们过不去
Jackson, you're sealed off! We can't get to you!
有东西卡住了液压装置
There's something blocking the hydraulics
如果不弄出来 我们都死定了
If you can't get it out, none of us are gonna make it
赫尔姆斯利博士 看这个
Dr. Helmsley, look at this.
下面全都淹没了
It's completely submerged down there
根本进不去 无法呼吸
and there's no way for them to get any air.
没别的办法了!
There is no other way!
但这是去送死 先生!
But it's a suicide mission, sir!
我知道卡在哪里 我去试试
I know where it is, I'll give it a try.
爸爸 等等 我要和你一起去!
Dad, wait, I wanna go with you!
- 不不不 - 爸爸我想帮你
- No, no, no. - Dad, I wanna help you! No, no, no.
- 你已经在帮我了 - 爸爸 求你了!
- You are helping me. - Dad, please!
还记得莉莉出生的时候
Remember when Lilly was born
你想当她哥哥吗?
and you wanted to be introduced as her big brother?
她现在很害怕
Well, she's scared now.
非常需要你
She needs you more than ever.
如果你安全 我就知道她也安全 明白吗?
If you're safe, I know that she's safe. Do you understand?
你可以下次再帮我
You can help me out the next time.
是我们把它卡住了
We caused this thing, it was us.
我得去搞定它
I gotta go check it out.
我爱你!
I love you!
丹增! 他不行了! 他不行了!
有人能听到我说话吗?
Can you hear me?
救命!
Help!
按住!
Press down!
用手按住!
Press down with your hand!
一直按住 别松手
Don't stop. Keep pressing!
不!
No!
距离撞击1850米
Distance to impact: 1,850 meters
看见他了
There he is!
船长 有影像了
Captain! We have a visual!
我们找到问题了
I think we found the problem.
切换到液压舱
Show us the hydraulics chamber
搞什么! 不是叫你留在上面吗!
God damn it! I told you to stay up there!
我只是想来帮你
I just wanted to help.
好吧 没事 你拿着手电筒
Alright, alright. You hold the light.
我们正在低压区 知道吗?
We're right under the air pocket, okay?
我还真的需要你帮忙
How did you know I needed help?
爷爷 奶奶 对不起
我救不了你们了
他会回来的 他会修好的
不可能的
不要灰心 哥哥
爸爸!
Dad!
没信号了 我们死定了
We lost him. We're gonna die!
干得好 照着那儿 我去拔电缆
Great job! You light the way and I'll go for the cable.
距离撞击400米
Distance to impact: 400 meters
前面有山脊!
Underwater ridge ahead!
我们要搁浅了 船长
We're going to run aground, Captain!
长官 门关上了
Sir, the gate is sealed!
确认了 船长!
That's affirmative, Captain!
- 安东 启动引擎 - 是 船长 全速后退
- Anton, start the engines. - Aye-aye Captain. Full reverse.
停不下来 船长 还是不行
Captain! We're not gonna make it!
距离撞击50米
Distance to impact: 50 meters.
40米
40 meters.
开始后退
Reverse motion activated
后退10米
Distance to impact: 10 meters.
20米
20 meters.
左满舵
Hard to port!
成功了! 我们成功了!
We did it! We did it!
- 爸爸呢? - 就在我后面
- Where's Dad? - He was right behind me
液压舱有消息吗?
Any word from the hydraulic chamber?
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
你不是说他在你后面吗?
I thought you said he was right behind you.
是啊
He was!
- 你确定吗? - 没错
- Are you sure? - Yes.
他明明就在那儿!
He was right there!
爸爸 爸爸!
Dad. Dad!
快点 杰克逊 出来啊
Come on, Jackson. Come on.
求你了 出来吧
Please, please.
出来啊
他成功了
He did it!
0001年1月27日
亚特兰蒂斯号太空船 我们的最后一天
Shuttle Atlantis. Our last day.
我们只能听到彼此的呼吸
All we can hear is the sound of our own breathing.
我们还在分享着共同的回忆 希望 和想法
That reminds us we are still sharing our memories, hopes and ideas.
有趣的是 直到今天早上我们才知道
And isn't it funny? Just this morning we worked it out
或多或少 我们在威斯康辛州都有亲戚
Somehow or another, we all have relatives in Wisconsin.
结束
The end.
真不错
It's good.
我就知道你会喜欢
I thought you would like it.
告诉我 威尔逊博士 除了书籍和艺术
Tell me Dr. Wilson, apart from books and art.
我们还有什么能分享的你觉得
Do you think there's anything else we might possibly share?
在未来
In the future?
赫尔姆斯利博士 你是在约我吗?
Are you asking me out on a date, Dr. Helmsley?
你知道我的行程都很紧凑的
You know my diary is pretty full.
事实上
Actually.
对 我是在约你
Yes, I was.
赫尔姆斯利博士请到控制舱
Dr. Helmsley to the bridge, please.
Dr. Helmsley to the bridge.
过来
Come here.
女士们先生们 我是迈克尔斯船长
Ladies and gentleman, this is captain Michaels speaking.
等一下 我将下令开启甲板
In a few minutes I will give orders to unseal the decks.
昨晚11点45分 6号和7号方舟和我们汇合了
At 23:45 last night, our sister Arks 6 and 7 have joined our course.
我们的旅程第一次出现了晴天 空气清澈
For the first time on our journey, we will have clear skies.
众所周知 我们的船严重超载
As you know our passenger count is way over capacity.
所以 请大家走上甲板时 格外小心
So please, be careful when you step out,
当然 好好享受新鲜空气吧
and of course, enjoy the fresh air.
我可以抱它吗?
Can I hold him?
当然 要是你喜欢 它也是你的
Sure, he can be your dog too if you like.
谢谢
Thanks.
我的真命天子 你去哪了?
Where have you been all my life?
去买礼物了
Gift shop.
嘿 艾德里安 好消息
Oh, Adrian. Excellent.
我们终于收到了卫星影像资料
I called because we just got our first satellite feet.
海底的变化
The equalization of the oceanic seabeds
并不像我们预料的那么糟糕
has not turned out to be as extreme as we expected.
海水在逐渐退去
The waters are receding.
比我们想像的快得多
Much faster than we thought.
感谢上帝 还有
Thank God. And,
这很难以置信
This is hard to believe.
不过 喜马拉雅山不再是世界屋脊了
But the Himalayas are no longer the roof of the world.
现在是尼泊尔 夸祖鲁的 德拉肯斯山脉
It's now the Drakensberg mountains of KwaZulu, Nepal.
非洲大陆板块整体上升了
The entire African continent has just risen.
七千英尺 以后不太可能被淹了
7.000 feet, and unlikely they are even flooded.
所以它才被称为充满希望的好望角
That's why they call it The Cape of Good Hope.
我们正向那里前进
We've already set course for it.
爹地 我们什么时候回家?
Daddy, when will we go back home?
这个嘛 我们讨论过了
Well, we talked about that.
我们打算在这里重新安家
We're gonna find a new home out here somewhere.
对吧?
Right?
只要我们在一起 那就是家了
Wherever we're all together. That's home.
对吧? 你害怕了吗?
Right? You are scared?
我才不害怕呢
I am not.
我不用纸尿裤了
No more pull-ups.
好极了
Nice.
片尾曲《奇迹来临的时刻》
主唱:亚当・兰伯特 (美国偶像第八季亚军)
∮夜已深 我无法入睡
∮对你思念太深
∮想起你的笑容 我几乎不能呼吸
∮每个亲吻我都无法忘记
∮这颗疼痛的心还没有碎
∮噢 上帝 我希望我能让你了解
∮因为我知道激情还没有消退
∮所以没有什么能阻止我努力
∮亲爱的你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮因为我不能对爱放弃
∮你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮我不能放弃我们
∮我只想与你在一起
∮因为生存是如此不容易
∮当我只知道要沉沦在你的眼里
∮对于未来我无法忘记
∮这颗疼痛的心还没有碎
∮噢 上帝 我希望我能让你了解
∮因为我知道激情还没有消退
∮所以没有什么能阻止我努力
∮亲爱的你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮因为我不能对爱放弃
∮你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮我不能放弃我们
∮亲爱的 你能感觉到它的来临吗?
∮你知道我能听见它 听见它 灵魂听得到
∮亲爱的 你感觉 他们感觉到你
∮你知道是时候了
∮亲爱的你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮因为我不能对爱放弃
∮你知道也许已是奇迹来临的时刻
∮不 我不能放弃我们
∮我不能放弃我们